const arr = [{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Posterior 1/3rd of the tongue is supplied by which nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Olfactory nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false}],"id":0},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following ions moves from endolymph to stereocilia to depolarize the hair cells?","answers":[{"option":"K+","bool":true},{"option":"Mg2+","bool":false},{"option":"Cl-","bool":false},{"option":"Ca2+","bool":false},{"option":"Na+","bool":false}],"id":1},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following branches of the maxillary artery passes through the foramen spinosum?","answers":[{"option":"Sphenopalatine artery","bool":false},{"option":"Middle meningeal artery","bool":true},{"option":"Nasopalatine artery","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory meningeal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Greater palatine artery","bool":false}],"id":2},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"What is the most common location for a thyroglossal duct cyst?","answers":[{"option":"Superior mediastinum","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior to hyoid bone","bool":true},{"option":"Superior to hyoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior to hyoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"At the base of tongue","bool":false}],"id":3},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Sensory retina develops from which part of the optic cup?","answers":[{"option":"Pars optica retinae","bool":true},{"option":"Pars caeca retinae","bool":false},{"option":"Pars iridica retinae","bool":false},{"option":"Pars ciliaris retinae","bool":false},{"option":"Outer layer of the optic cup","bool":false}],"id":4},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which is not present in the carotid sheath?","answers":[{"option":"Internal carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Internal jugular vein","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"External jugular vein","bool":true},{"option":"Common carotid artery","bool":false}],"id":5},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following muscles is not supplied by the mandibular nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Medial pterygoid","bool":false},{"option":"Temporalis","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral pterygoid","bool":false},{"option":"Masseter","bool":false},{"option":"Buccinator","bool":true}],"id":6},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"A person injures his mandible (ramus) in an accident. Which boundary of the wall of the infratemporal fossa does it form?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior wall","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral wall","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior wall","bool":false},{"option":"Medial wall","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior wall","bool":false}],"id":7},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"While examining the lateral view of the X-ray of the skull, a radiologist points out a region that is the meeting point of the parietomastoid, occipitomastoid, and lambdoid sutures. What point is he referring to?","answers":[{"option":"Inion","bool":false},{"option":"Lambda","bool":false},{"option":"Pterion","bool":false},{"option":"Bregma","bool":false},{"option":"Asterion","bool":true}],"id":8},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which muscle takes part in the formation of palatine aponeurosis?","answers":[{"option":"Musculus uvulae","bool":false},{"option":"Tensor veli palatini","bool":true},{"option":"Tensor tympani","bool":false},{"option":"Palatoglossus","bool":false},{"option":"Palatopharyngeus","bool":false}],"id":9},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"A girl wearing tops suffers an infection. Which of the following lymph nodes would be involved?","answers":[{"option":"Maxillary nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Deep cervical nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Axillary nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial cervical nodes","bool":true},{"option":"Mastoid nodes","bool":false}],"id":10},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"In which of the following structures does the nasolacrimal duct open into?","answers":[{"option":"Superior meatus","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Infraorbital foramen","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior meatus","bool":true},{"option":"Middle meatus","bool":false}],"id":11},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"The pterygoid venous plexus drains into which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"External jugular vein","bool":false},{"option":"Cavernous sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Middle meningeal vein","bool":false},{"option":"Facial vein","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary vein","bool":true}],"id":12},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Correction of cleft lip usually occurs during which month?","answers":[{"option":"3rd month","bool":true},{"option":"6th month","bool":false},{"option":"10th month","bool":false},{"option":"12th month","bool":false},{"option":"9th month","bool":false}],"id":13},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"The lymphatic drainage from the palatine tonsil drains into which of the following lymph nodes?","answers":[{"option":"Superficial cervical","bool":false},{"option":"Deep cervical","bool":false},{"option":"Submental","bool":false},{"option":"Submandibular","bool":false},{"option":"Jugulodigastric","bool":true}],"id":14},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Lymph from tongue drain in which of the following lymph nodes?","answers":[{"option":"Deep cervical","bool":false},{"option":"Supraclavicular","bool":false},{"option":"Submental","bool":false},{"option":"Jugulodigastric","bool":false},{"option":"Jugulo-omohyoid","bool":true}],"id":15},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which one of the following is not a tributary of the external jugular vein?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior branch of retromandibular vein","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior auricular vein","bool":false},{"option":"Suprascapular vein","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior jugular vein","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior branch of retromandibular vein","bool":false}],"id":16},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which of the following nerves supplies the skin over the angle of the mandible?","answers":[{"option":"Greater auricular nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Lesser auricular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Long thoracic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior auricular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Mandibular nerve","bool":false}],"id":17},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following arteries is not a branch of the external carotid artery?","answers":[{"option":"Superior thyroid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Facial","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior thyroid artery","bool":true},{"option":"Sphenopalatine artery","bool":false},{"option":"Occipital","bool":false}],"id":18},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which structure does not take part in the formation of an external nose?","answers":[{"option":"Maxillary bone","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal cartilages","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior conchae","bool":true},{"option":"All of these take part","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal bone","bool":false}],"id":19},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"Which of the following structures does not pass through the foramen ovale?","answers":[{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Middle meningeal artery","bool":true},{"option":"Mandibular division of trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Lesser petrosal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory meningeal artery","bool":false}],"id":20},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Where does the aqueous humor drain into?","answers":[{"option":"Scleral venous sinus","bool":true},{"option":"Sigmoidal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Ethmoidal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Cavernous sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Sagittal sinus","bool":false}],"id":21},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is present in the optic canal?","answers":[{"option":"Ophthalmic artery","bool":true},{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Infraorbital nerve","bool":false}],"id":22},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"The gland that secretes calcitonin is formed from which pharyngeal pouch?","answers":[{"option":"5th","bool":false},{"option":"1st","bool":false},{"option":"3rd","bool":false},{"option":"4th","bool":true},{"option":"2nd","bool":false}],"id":23},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"A 63-year-old man fails to maintain balance during linear motion. Which of the following sensory organs is responsible for detecting linear acceleration?","answers":[{"option":"Organ of corti","bool":false},{"option":"Cochlear duct","bool":false},{"option":"Cristae","bool":false},{"option":"Saccules","bool":false},{"option":"Maculae","bool":true}],"id":24},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following cells mainly causes lateral inhibition?","answers":[{"option":"Ganglionic cells","bool":false},{"option":"Amacrine cells","bool":false},{"option":"Horizontal cells","bool":true},{"option":"Rods","bool":false},{"option":"Bipolar cells","bool":false}],"id":25},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"What substance combines with scotopsin to form rhodopsin?","answers":[{"option":"11-cis retinol","bool":false},{"option":"11-cis retinal","bool":true},{"option":"All-trans retinol","bool":false},{"option":"13-cis retinol","bool":false},{"option":"All-trans retinal","bool":false}],"id":26},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Taste buds are present in the following papillae except:","answers":[{"option":"Filliform","bool":true},{"option":"Fulliform","bool":false},{"option":"Circumvalate","bool":false},{"option":"Foliate","bool":false},{"option":"Fungiform","bool":false}],"id":27},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Taste fibres from circumvallate papillae pass through what nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Maxillary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Chorda tympani","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false}],"id":28},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Axons of which cells form the optic nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Bipolar cells","bool":false},{"option":"Rod cells","bool":false},{"option":"Horizontal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Amacrine cells","bool":false},{"option":"Ganglion cells","bool":true}],"id":29},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Dorsum of the tongue is lined by which epithelium?","answers":[{"option":"Pseudostratified columnar","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified columnar","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous non-keratinized","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous keratinized","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous partially keratinized","bool":true}],"id":30},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"A clinician examines the extrinsic musculature of the eyes of a 50-year-old female patient. All extraocular muscles are functioning fine except one. Which of the following muscles is affected based on the action mentioned?","answers":[{"option":"Superior oblique-looks medially and upwards","bool":true},{"option":"Medial rectus- looks medially","bool":false},{"option":"Superior rectus-looks medially and upwards","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior rectus-looks downwards","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral rectus-looks laterally","bool":false}],"id":31},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is a feature of complete anterior cleft anomaly?","answers":[{"option":"Cleft extends through maxilla and hard palate","bool":false},{"option":"Cleft extends through lips and alveolar part of maxilla","bool":false},{"option":"Cleft extends through lip, maxilla, soft palate, and hard palate","bool":false},{"option":"Cleft extends through lips and alveolar part of maxilla to the incisive fossa on both sides","bool":false},{"option":"Cleft extends through upper lip and alveolar part of maxilla to the incisive fossa","bool":true}],"id":32},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"A surgeon, while performing surgery for removal of lymph nodes from the posterior triangle of the neck, is liable to damage which one of the following nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Maxillary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Supraclavicular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Lesser occipital nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Greater auricular nerve","bool":false}],"id":33},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding the features of the pigmented epithelium layer of the retina?","answers":[{"option":"It consists of simple columnar epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"The cells show phagocytic activity","bool":false},{"option":"It consists of stratified columnar epithelium","bool":true},{"option":"It strongly adheres to Bruch's membrane of choroid","bool":false},{"option":"It contains stores of vitamin A","bool":false}],"id":34},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is not a feature of a typical cervical vertebra?","answers":[{"option":"Triangular vertebral foramen","bool":false},{"option":"Body","bool":false},{"option":"Bifid spinous process","bool":false},{"option":"Transverse foramen","bool":false},{"option":"Dens","bool":true}],"id":35},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which bone has a major contribution to the formation of the nasal septum?","answers":[{"option":"Nasal spine of frontal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary palatine crest","bool":false},{"option":"Rostrum of sphenoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"Perpendicular plate of ethmoid bone","bool":true},{"option":"Perpendicular plate of palatine bone","bool":false}],"id":36},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"A lesion of the optic chiasma causes which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Loss of vision in the left eye","bool":false},{"option":"Homonymous contralateral hemianopsia","bool":false},{"option":"Homonymous hemianopsia","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of vision in the right eye","bool":false},{"option":"Heteronymous bitemporal hemianopsia","bool":true}],"id":37},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"The auditory ossicles articulate through which kind of joint?","answers":[{"option":"Fibrocartilaginous joint","bool":false},{"option":"Synovial joint","bool":true},{"option":"Fibrous joint","bool":false},{"option":"Cartilaginous joint","bool":false},{"option":"Syndesmoses","bool":false}],"id":38},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"The transverse facial artery is a branch of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior auricular artery","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial temporal artery","bool":true},{"option":"Occipital artery","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary artery","bool":false},{"option":"Facial artery","bool":false}],"id":39},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"The rhombencephalic isthmus separates which parts of the brain?","answers":[{"option":"Mesencephalon from the metencephalon","bool":true},{"option":"Myelencephalon from the spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Rhombencephalon from the mesencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Metencephalon from the myelencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Prosencephalon from the diencephalon","bool":false}],"id":40},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which facial nerve branches are present in the middle ear?","answers":[{"option":"Chorda tympani and greater petrosal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Chorda tympani and nerve to stapedius","bool":true},{"option":"Deep petrosal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vidian nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Greater petrosal nerve and nerve to stapedius","bool":false}],"id":41},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"A young man had a car accident and came to the emergency room (ER) with a fracture of a facial bone that is unpaired. Which bone is involved?","answers":[{"option":"Mandible bone","bool":true},{"option":"Nasal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary bone","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Zygomatic bone","bool":false}],"id":42},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which nerve supplies the general sensation for the anterior 2/3rd of the tongue?","answers":[{"option":"Hypoglossal","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual","bool":true},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal","bool":false},{"option":"Facial","bool":false}],"id":43},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"The speech and tone are produced with the assistance of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Larynx","bool":false},{"option":"Tongue","bool":true},{"option":"Pharynx","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Tonsils","bool":false}],"id":44},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is true regarding the structure of taste buds?","answers":[{"option":"They are mainly located on the soft palate but few on the ventral surface of tongue","bool":false},{"option":"A taste bud consists of 10-12 cells","bool":false},{"option":"Sustentacular cells of taste buds are also known as gustatory cells","bool":false},{"option":"Apex of the taste buds communicate with the oral cavity through taste pore","bool":true},{"option":"Taste buds are embedded within epithelium covering the  filiform papillae","bool":false}],"id":45},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Sensory innervation of laryngopharynx is by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"External laryngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Recurrent laryngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Internal branch of superior laryngeal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Pharyngeal branch of maxillary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false}],"id":46},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is incorrect about salivary glands?","answers":[{"option":"Serous cell are predominant cells of submandibular gland","bool":false},{"option":"Intercalated ducts are wider and longer in the parotid gland","bool":false},{"option":"All minor salivary gland are not encapsulated","bool":false},{"option":"All minor salivary glands are serous in nature","bool":true},{"option":"Demilune cells secrete lysozyme in sublingual gland","bool":false}],"id":47},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"The auditory ossicle(s) attached to the oval window is/are derived from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Mandibular arch","bool":false},{"option":"3rd pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"4th pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"Hyoid arch","bool":true},{"option":"1st pharyngeal arch","bool":false}],"id":48},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Where are the infrahyoid muscles present?","answers":[{"option":"Submental triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Muscular triangle","bool":true},{"option":"Submandibular triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Carotid triangle","bool":false}],"id":49},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"The parafollicular cells (C-cells) of the thyroid are derived from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Second pharyngeal pouch","bool":false},{"option":"Third pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"First pharyngeal pouch","bool":false},{"option":"Ultimobranchial body","bool":true},{"option":"Second pharyngeal cleft","bool":false}],"id":50},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which nucleus in the brainstem receives fibers carrying taste sensations?","answers":[{"option":"Dorsal nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus ambiguus","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus of pneumotaxic centre","bool":false},{"option":"Vasomotor centre","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus of tractus solitarius","bool":true}],"id":51},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which is true regarding the venous drainage of face?","answers":[{"option":"Facial vein communicates with inferior ophthalmic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Facial vein drains into external jugular vein","bool":false},{"option":"Facial vein has unidirectional valves","bool":false},{"option":"Facial vein communicates with cavernous sinus through angular vein","bool":false},{"option":"Deep facial vein drains into the pterygoid plexus","bool":true}],"id":52},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"The axons of ganglionic cells transmitting action potential synapse in the midbrain with which of the following structure?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior colliculus","bool":false},{"option":"Optic radiation","bool":false},{"option":"Superior colliculus","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral geniculate body","bool":false},{"option":"Medial geniculate body","bool":false}],"id":53},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"The nasolacrimal duct opens into which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Infundibulum","bool":false},{"option":"Superior meatus","bool":false},{"option":"Hiatus semilunaris","bool":false},{"option":"Spheno-ethmoidal recess","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior meatus","bool":true}],"id":54},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is the relation of the facial nerve with the parotid gland?","answers":[{"option":"Deep to gland","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial to artery","bool":false},{"option":"Deep to arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial to gland","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial to vein","bool":true}],"id":55},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"The triangular primary palate is formed by the fusion of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Medial nasal prominence","bool":true},{"option":"Maxillary prominence with lateral nasal prominence","bool":false},{"option":"Two lateral nasal prominence","bool":false},{"option":"Two maxillary prominence","bool":false},{"option":"Two mandibular prominence","bool":false}],"id":56},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Visual fibers also pass through the pretectal nucleus in the midbrain. Pretectal nucleus is associated with which of the following function?","answers":[{"option":"Pupillary light reflex","bool":true},{"option":"Attenuation reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Balance and equilibrium","bool":false},{"option":"Color sensation","bool":false},{"option":"Accommodation reflex","bool":false}],"id":57},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding the lacrimal apparatus?","answers":[{"option":"Tears flow to the lacrimal puncta","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal glands drain into superficial parotid lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Tears collect in the conjunctival fornix","bool":false},{"option":"Secretions produced are called tears","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal glands are of simple tubuloacinar type","bool":true}],"id":58},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Aphakia is associated with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudoaphakia","bool":false},{"option":"Astigmatism","bool":false},{"option":"Hyphema","bool":false},{"option":"Hypermetropia","bool":true}],"id":59},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"In lateral view of an X-ray of the head, a physician notices the meeting point of parietooccipital, occipitomastoid, and lambdoid sutures. What is this point called?","answers":[{"option":"Asterion","bool":true},{"option":"Inion","bool":false},{"option":"Lambda","bool":false},{"option":"Pterion","bool":false},{"option":"Bregma","bool":false}],"id":60},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which is not true about the retina?","answers":[{"option":"It terminates at ora serrata","bool":false},{"option":"It is highly vascular","bool":false},{"option":"It is the photoreceptor layer","bool":false},{"option":"Two retinal layers can easily be detached","bool":false},{"option":"The innermost layer of the retina contains the rods and cones","bool":true}],"id":61},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"The deficiency of vitamin A causes a pathological condition called xerophthalmia. Which of the following correctly describes it?","answers":[{"option":"Poor vision in dim light","bool":false},{"option":"Dryness of the cornea and conjuctiva","bool":true},{"option":"Thickening of a part of cornea","bool":false},{"option":"Poor vision at night","bool":false},{"option":"Dryness of cornea along with cloudy appearance","bool":false}],"id":62},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"In the case of vitamin A deficiency, keratomalacia occurs. Which of the following characterizes this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Dryness of conjunctiva and cornea","bool":false},{"option":"Unable to see in light or dark condition","bool":false},{"option":"Patient cannot see in low light or in near dark condition","bool":false},{"option":"Localized thickening of conjunctiva","bool":false},{"option":"Dryness and clouding of cornea","bool":true}],"id":63},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"An oblique facial cleft is a developmental anomaly that occurs due to failure of fusion of which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Two maxillary prominence with each other","bool":false},{"option":"Two mandibular prominence with each other","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary prominence with medial nasal prominence","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary prominence with lateral nasal prominence","bool":true},{"option":"Two medial nasal prominence with each other","bool":false}],"id":64},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Pterygoid venous plexus is a network of veins that drains into which of the following vein?","answers":[{"option":"Maxillary vein","bool":true},{"option":"Cavernous sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior ophthalmic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Superior ophthalmic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Facial vein","bool":false}],"id":65},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"The swallowing center is located in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla oblongata","bool":true},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Midbrain","bool":false}],"id":66},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"The infraorbital foramen is an opening in which of the following bones?","answers":[{"option":"Maxillary bone","bool":true},{"option":"Ethmoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"Zygomatic bone","bool":false},{"option":"Greater wing of the sphenoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal bone","bool":false}],"id":67},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following nerves provide sensory supply to the skin overlying the angle of the mandible?","answers":[{"option":"Mandibular branch of trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Lesser occipital nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary branch of trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Greater auricular nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Greater occipital nerve","bool":false}],"id":68},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"A person presents with his right eye looking \"down and out\" with double vision (diplopia) when looking at the right. He has a lesion in which of the following nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Right oculomotor nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Right trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Left trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Left trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Left oculomotor nerve","bool":false}],"id":69},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"The submandibular lymph nodes are present in which triangle?","answers":[{"option":"Submental triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Digastric triangle","bool":true},{"option":"Muscular triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Carotid triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Omohyoid triangle","bool":false}],"id":70},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following equalizes the pressure between the external atmosphere and the middle ear cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Eustachian tube","bool":true},{"option":"Auricle","bool":false},{"option":"External ear","bool":false},{"option":"Tympanic membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Pinna","bool":false}],"id":71},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"What happens to the vocal cords while swallowing?","answers":[{"option":"Opened","bool":false},{"option":"Gapped by membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Approximated","bool":true},{"option":"No change","bool":false},{"option":"Overlapped","bool":false}],"id":72},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"A teacher discussed a fossa inferior and deep to the zygomatic arch and posterior to the maxilla. The appropriate fossa being discussed is?","answers":[{"option":"Pterygopalatine","bool":false},{"option":"Occipital","bool":false},{"option":"Middle cranial","bool":false},{"option":"Infratemporal","bool":true},{"option":"Temporal","bool":false}],"id":73},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"The suspensory ligaments of the eye are an extension of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Orbital septum","bool":false},{"option":"Tenon's capsule","bool":true},{"option":"Deep fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Periorbital fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial fascia","bool":false}],"id":74},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"A man received a strong blow to the anterior aspect of the mandible during a fight. The tympanic plate of the external auditory meatus was affected. The temporomandibular joint has undergone which type of dislocation?","answers":[{"option":"Superior","bool":false},{"option":"Medial","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral","bool":false}],"id":75},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"A student is studying about a muscle that forms the boundaries of both anterior and posterior triangles. Which of the following is the appropriate muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Levator scapulae","bool":false},{"option":"Sternocleidomastoid","bool":true},{"option":"Suprahyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Infrahyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Trapezius","bool":false}],"id":76},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which nucleus of the thalamus is responsible for carrying fibers to the auditory cortex?","answers":[{"option":"Venteroposterolateral nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsomedial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Ventroposteromedial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral geniculate body","bool":false},{"option":"Medial geniculate body","bool":true}],"id":77},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following muscles causes forceful closure of the eyes?","answers":[{"option":"Procerus","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal part of orbicularis oculi","bool":false},{"option":"Orbital part of orbicularis oculi","bool":true},{"option":"Palpebral part of orbicularis oculi","bool":false}],"id":78},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which structure does not pass through the superior orbital fissure?","answers":[{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Superior ophthalmic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":false}],"id":79},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"A girl is facing pre-pubertal acne. The doctor warns her about not squeezing any pimples and prescribes her some special cream for the tip of the nose and the upper lip region acne. What is the most likely reason?","answers":[{"option":"This area requires more special care than the others","bool":false},{"option":"This area is more prone to acne","bool":false},{"option":"This area is richly vascularized","bool":false},{"option":"This area has direct dural venous drainage","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":80},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following structures is a content of the pterygopalatine fossa?","answers":[{"option":"3rd part of the maxillary artery","bool":true},{"option":"Infraorbital nerve","bool":false},{"option":"2nd part of maxillary artery","bool":false},{"option":"Otic ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"1st part of the maxillary artery","bool":false}],"id":81},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Umami taste fibers are related to?","answers":[{"option":"Organic substances containing nitrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Fructose","bool":false},{"option":"Alkaloids","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamate","bool":true},{"option":"Acetic acid","bool":false}],"id":82},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Myopia is corrected by what type of lens?","answers":[{"option":"Convex","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Imaginary","bool":false},{"option":"Mixed","bool":false},{"option":"Concave","bool":true}],"id":83},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"What is the position of the macula lutea relative to the optic disc in the eyeball?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral","bool":true},{"option":"Medial","bool":false},{"option":"Superior","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior","bool":false}],"id":84},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Anesthesia in retromolar fossa primarily blocks which of the following nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Mental nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Submandibular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior alveolar nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Buccal nerve","bool":true}],"id":85},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Fracture of mandible most likely results in the damage of which of the following nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Lingual nerve","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Submandibular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior alveolar nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Buccal nerve","bool":false}],"id":86},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"A patient comes to the outpatient department with complaints of dryness of nose and palate. Which ganglion must be damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Pterygopalatine ganglion","bool":true},{"option":"Otic ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Submandibular ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Nodose ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Ciliary ganglion","bool":false}],"id":87},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which type of gland is the gland of Zeis?","answers":[{"option":"Mucus glands","bool":false},{"option":"Modified lacrimal glands","bool":false},{"option":"Modified sebaceous glands","bool":true},{"option":"Mebomian glands","bool":false},{"option":"Modified sweat glands","bool":false}],"id":88},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is true about the canal of Schlemm?","answers":[{"option":"It is lined by stratified squamous epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"It is lined by endothelium","bool":true},{"option":"It contains red cells","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"It communicates with the vitreous chamber","bool":false}],"id":89},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Ethmoidal bulla can be seen in the middle nasal meatus. Which of the following is related to ethmoidal bulla?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior ethmoidal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Middle ethmoidal sinus","bool":true},{"option":"Frontal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior ethmoidal sinus","bool":false}],"id":90},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Nasolacrimal duct drains tears to which of the following parts of the nose?","answers":[{"option":"Superior nasal meatus","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal sac","bool":false},{"option":"Middle nasal meatus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior nasal conchae","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior nasal meatus","bool":true}],"id":91},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"A second year MBBS student performed experiments related to the sense of taste in the physiology lab. Which of the following taste sensation will have the lowest stimulation threshold?","answers":[{"option":"Acid","bool":false},{"option":"Sweet","bool":false},{"option":"Salty","bool":false},{"option":"Sour","bool":false},{"option":"Bitter","bool":true}],"id":92},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"Rods are concentrated in which of the following regions?","answers":[{"option":"Nissels Granules","bool":false},{"option":"Parafoveal region","bool":true},{"option":"Synaptic bulb","bool":false},{"option":"Maculae","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false}],"id":93},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"The auditory tube is found in which of the following walls of middle ear cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior wall","bool":true},{"option":"Roof","bool":false},{"option":"Floor","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral wall","bool":false},{"option":"Medial wall","bool":false}],"id":94},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"Which of the following nerves supplies the nasopharynx?","answers":[{"option":"Maxillary nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Ophthalmic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"All of them","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false}],"id":95},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"Third-order neurons of the olfactory bulb terminate into which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Basal ganglia","bool":false},{"option":"Temporal lobe","bool":true},{"option":"Thalamus","bool":false}],"id":96},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"Which of the following is not a derivative of 2nd pharyngeal arch?","answers":[{"option":"Stylohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Stapedius","bool":false},{"option":"Levator veli palatini","bool":true},{"option":"Buccinator","bool":false}],"id":97},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"Which of the following ways is used to calculate intelligence quotient (IQ)?","answers":[{"option":"Dividing mental age by chronological age","bool":true},{"option":"Multiplying mental age with chronological age","bool":false},{"option":"Subtracting chronological age from mental age","bool":false},{"option":"Dividing chronological age by mental age","bool":false},{"option":"Subtracting mental age from chronological age","bool":false}],"id":98},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"Which of the following structures is formed by the union of the retromandibular vein and posterior auricular vein?","answers":[{"option":"External jugular vein","bool":true},{"option":"Superficial temporal vein","bool":false},{"option":"Subclavian vein","bool":false},{"option":"Common facial vein","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary vein","bool":false}],"id":99},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"Which of the following is not a branch of facial artery?","answers":[{"option":"Superior labial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Submental artery","bool":false},{"option":"Transverse facial artery","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior labial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral nasal artery","bool":false}],"id":100},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"Which of the following structures passes through the parotid gland?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Internal carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Internal jugular vein","bool":false},{"option":"Facial vein","bool":false}],"id":101},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"When is the upper lip and palate formed?","answers":[{"option":"3rd-4th weeks of pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"21st-23rd weeks of pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"4th-5th weeks of pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"6th-9th weeks of pregnancy","bool":true},{"option":"13th-18th weeks of pregnancy","bool":false}],"id":102},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"Which of the following structures divides the parotid gland into superficial and deep parts?","answers":[{"option":"Retromandibular vein","bool":false},{"option":"Facial vein","bool":false},{"option":"Facial artery","bool":false},{"option":"External carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":true}],"id":103},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"What is the collective name given to all refractive errors in both eyes?","answers":[{"option":"Anisometropia","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Amblyopia","bool":false},{"option":"Astigmatism","bool":false},{"option":"Ametropia","bool":true}],"id":104},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"Which of the following is the most common benign tumor of parotid gland?","answers":[{"option":"Acinic cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Myoepithelioma","bool":false},{"option":"Pleomorphic adenoma","bool":true},{"option":"Canalicular adenoma","bool":false},{"option":"Basal cell adenoma","bool":false}],"id":105},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"The nerve supplying the muscles of mastication exits the skull through which of the following foramens?","answers":[{"option":"Foramen ovale","bool":true},{"option":"Mental foramen","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen spinosum","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen rotundum","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen lacerum","bool":false}],"id":106},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"Which of the following is not true regarding trochlear nerve?","answers":[{"option":"It passes through the cavernous sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Lesion results in upward deviation and lateral rotation","bool":true},{"option":"It supplies superior oblique","bool":false},{"option":"It supplies extraocular muscles","bool":false},{"option":"It is the only nerve arising from the back of brain stem","bool":false}],"id":107},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"The scalp terminates at which of the following layers?","answers":[{"option":"Skin","bool":false},{"option":"Aponeurosis","bool":false},{"option":"Epicranium","bool":false},{"option":"Connective tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Pericranium","bool":true}],"id":108},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"Which of the following antibodies is released by the parotid gland?","answers":[{"option":"IgM","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"IgD","bool":false},{"option":"IgA","bool":true},{"option":"IgE","bool":false}],"id":109},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"Which nerve innervates the tip of the tongue?","answers":[{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Mandibular nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false}],"id":110},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"Which of the following tongue papillae contain the greatest number of taste buds?","answers":[{"option":"Fungiform papillae","bool":false},{"option":"Circumvallate papillae","bool":true},{"option":"Filiform papillae","bool":false},{"option":"Foliate papillae","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false}],"id":111},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"By the fifth week of pregnancy, six auricular hillocks appear on the face. These are the primordia of which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Eyes","bool":false},{"option":"Internal ear","bool":false},{"option":"Tongue","bool":false},{"option":"External ear","bool":true},{"option":"Nose","bool":false}],"id":112},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"Which of the following boundaries of stomodeum are formed by maxillary prominences?","answers":[{"option":"Rostral","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Caudal","bool":false}],"id":113},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"Damage to which of the following muscles results in an inability to move the chin to the opposite side?","answers":[{"option":"Masseter","bool":false},{"option":"Buccinator","bool":false},{"option":"Levator scapulae","bool":false},{"option":"Temporalis","bool":false},{"option":"Sternocleidomastoid","bool":true}],"id":114},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"Which of the following structures are not present in posterior triangle of neck?","answers":[{"option":"Supraclavicular lymph nodes","bool":true},{"option":"Trunks of brachial plexus","bool":false},{"option":"Cervical plexus","bool":false},{"option":"Subclavian artery","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory nerve","bool":false}],"id":115},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"Which of the following statements is true regarding Stenson's duct?","answers":[{"option":"It is a duct of the submandibular gland","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"It is a duct of the sublingual gland","bool":false},{"option":"It pierces the buccinator muscle","bool":true},{"option":"It arises from posterior surface of parotid gland","bool":false}],"id":116},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"In cephalohematoma, fluid is present between which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Dura and arachnoid","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Dural folds","bool":false},{"option":"Skull and periosteum","bool":true},{"option":"Arachnoid and pia","bool":false}],"id":117},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"Right homonymous hemianopia cannot be possible with lesion of which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Visual cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Optic chiasm","bool":true},{"option":"Optic tract","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Optic radiation","bool":false}],"id":118},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"An infarct of which of the following arteries will result in homonymous hemianopia?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Middle cerebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior cerebral artery","bool":true}],"id":119},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"Which of the following muscles is responsible for opening of mouth?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral pterygoid","bool":true},{"option":"Temporalis","bool":false},{"option":"Masseter","bool":false},{"option":"Medial pterygoid","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":120},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"What is the principle of Rinne's test?","answers":[{"option":"Bone conduction is better than air conduction","bool":false},{"option":"Air conduction is the same as bone conduction","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Air conduction is better than bone conduction","bool":true},{"option":"All of these","bool":false}],"id":121},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"Lateralization to left ear can indicate which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Sensorineural hearing loss in left ear","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Sensorineural hearing loss in right ear","bool":true},{"option":"Conductive hearing loss in right ear","bool":false},{"option":"Combined hearing loss in left ear","bool":false}],"id":122},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2016"],"question":"Which of the following are most likely to affect an individual’s personality?","answers":[{"option":"Gender","bool":false},{"option":"Health","bool":false},{"option":"Physical capabilities","bool":false},{"option":"Temperament","bool":true},{"option":"Skin color","bool":false}],"id":123},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which of the following parts of the ear connects the middle ear with the nasopharynx?","answers":[{"option":"Auditory ossicles","bool":false},{"option":"Tympanic cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Tympanic membrane","bool":false},{"option":"External acoustic meatus","bool":false},{"option":"Pharyngotympanic tube","bool":true}],"id":124},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which of the following muscles acts synergetically with the masseter to elevate the mandible and produce smaller grinding movements?","answers":[{"option":"Mylohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Geniohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral pterygoid","bool":false},{"option":"Medial pterygoid","bool":true},{"option":"Temporalis","bool":false}],"id":125},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which bone of the basicranium is formed by endochondral ossification?","answers":[{"option":"Frontal","bool":false},{"option":"Vomer","bool":false},{"option":"Parietal","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenoidal","bool":true},{"option":"Lacrimal","bool":false}],"id":126},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which of the following foramina is present as a large opening between the occipital bone and the petrous part of the temporal bone?","answers":[{"option":"Stylomastoid foramen","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen spinosum","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen lacerum","bool":false},{"option":"Jugular foramen","bool":true}],"id":127},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Complete the following: At the lower border of the posterior belly of the digastric muscle, the hypoglossal nerve turns forward and medially...","answers":[{"option":"Loops around the occipital artery","bool":false},{"option":"Deep to the submandibular gland","bool":false},{"option":"Loops around the lingual artery","bool":false},{"option":"Deep to the lingual nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Loops around the occipital artery and crosses the external and internal carotid","bool":true}],"id":128},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is the correct statement regarding the histology of the tongue?","answers":[{"option":"Taste buds are only found in filiform papillae","bool":false},{"option":"Filiform papillae are most numerous and keratinized","bool":true},{"option":"Dorsal surface of tongue is smooth and shows prominent lingual veins","bool":false},{"option":"Circumvalate papillae are present behind the sulcus terminalis","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual papillae are formed of stratified squamous epithelium only","bool":false}],"id":129},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Regarding the gross features of the larynx, which of the following is true?","answers":[{"option":"Corniculate is a small rod shaped cartilage present on the upper lateral part of the cricoid cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"Arytenoid cartilage is small pyramidal in shape, lying on the inferior cornu of thyroid","bool":false},{"option":"Epiglottis is a a leaf shaped cartilage places in the posterior wall of the larynx","bool":false},{"option":"Upper part of the anterior border of the thyroid cartilage is separated by the thyroid notch","bool":true},{"option":"Thyroid cartilage is shaped like a ring and is elastic in nature","bool":false}],"id":130},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is correct regarding the gross features of the skull and norma frontalis?","answers":[{"option":"The bridge of the nose is formed by the frontal and zygomatic bones","bool":false},{"option":"The nasion is a median point of the root of the nose","bool":true},{"option":"Frontal eminence is a low, rounded elevation between two superciliary arches","bool":false},{"option":"Supraorbital margin of the orbital cavity is formed by the zygomatic bone","bool":false},{"option":"Glabella is a median elevation in the nasal bone","bool":false}],"id":131},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is correct regarding gross anatomical features of the scalp?","answers":[{"option":"Behind the auricle of the scalp, it is supplied by the branches of the superficial temporal arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Loose areolar tissue extends anteriorly to the supraorbital margins of the frontal bone","bool":true},{"option":"Epicranial aponeurosis is tightly applied to the pericranium","bool":false},{"option":"Skin of the scalp is devoid of sebaceous glands","bool":false},{"option":"In front of the auricle, the scalp is supplied by the branches of the ophthalmic artery","bool":false}],"id":132},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Regarding the gross features of the norma occipitalis and normal lateralis, which of the following is the correct statement?","answers":[{"option":"Lambdoid suture lies between the frontal and parietal bones","bool":false},{"option":"External occipital protuberance is a median protuberance in the norma occipitalis that marks the junction of the head and neck","bool":true},{"option":"Floor of the infratemporal fossa is pierced by the foramen ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Temporal lines are continuous from the norma lateralis to norma occipitalis","bool":false},{"option":"Roof of the infratemporal fossa is formed by the lesser wing of the sphenoid","bool":false}],"id":133},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"The orbicularis oris, the muscle of facial expression, is inserted on which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Mucous membranes of the lips","bool":true},{"option":"Skin of lower lip","bool":false},{"option":"Skin of upper lip","bool":false},{"option":"Major alar cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"Skin around the orbital margin","bool":false}],"id":134},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"The mental artery supplying the muscles of the face is best described as a branch of which artery?","answers":[{"option":"Smaller terminal branch of the external carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"External carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Internal carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Terminal branch of the facial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Terminal branch of inferior alveolar artery","bool":true}],"id":135},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"The superior oblique muscle, attached to the body of the sphenoid, is innervated by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor nerve","bool":false}],"id":136},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"The intermaxillary segment gives rise to which of the following structures in the development of the face?","answers":[{"option":"Soft palate","bool":false},{"option":"Primary palate","bool":true},{"option":"Upper molar arches","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary palate","bool":false},{"option":"Lower incisor teeth","bool":false}],"id":137},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"The olfactory epithelium is derived from which embryonic structure?","answers":[{"option":"Neuroectoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Surface ectoderm","bool":true},{"option":"Endoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Neural crest cells","bool":false},{"option":"Mesoderm","bool":false}],"id":138},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"The secretory part of the parotid gland is derived from which of the following germ layers?","answers":[{"option":"Endoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Neural crest cell","bool":false},{"option":"Neuroectoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Mesoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Ectoderm","bool":true}],"id":139},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"The external acoustic meatus develops from which of the following parts of the pharyngeal apparatus?","answers":[{"option":"Tubotympanic recess","bool":false},{"option":"1st pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"2nd pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"1st pharyngeal groove","bool":true},{"option":"1st pharyngeal membrane","bool":false}],"id":140},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Hemorrhage in tonsil surgery is due to which of the following vessels?","answers":[{"option":"Maxillary vein","bool":false},{"option":"Paratonsillar vein","bool":true},{"option":"Lingual artery","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary artery","bool":false},{"option":"Brachial artery","bool":false}],"id":141},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which of the following leads to the development of the cerebellum?","answers":[{"option":"Metencephalon","bool":true},{"option":"Rhombencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Prosencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Telencephalon","bool":false}],"id":142},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Tuning of sound is a function of turbinates in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Internal ear","bool":false},{"option":"Pharynx","bool":false},{"option":"Nose","bool":true},{"option":"Face","bool":false},{"option":"Vocal cord","bool":false}],"id":143},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which of the following bones is not involved in pterion formation?","answers":[{"option":"Temporal","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenoid","bool":false},{"option":"Parietal","bool":false},{"option":"Occipital","bool":true}],"id":144},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which of the following does not pass through the superior orbital fissure?","answers":[{"option":"Ophthalmic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":true}],"id":145},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"The lymph from the ear lobule is drained into which of the following lymph nodes?","answers":[{"option":"Deep cervical nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial cervical nodes","bool":true},{"option":"Superficial inguinal nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Submandibular nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Submental nodes","bool":false}],"id":146},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which of the following statements is not true for the pterygoid venous plexus?","answers":[{"option":"Receives blood from branches of maxillary artery","bool":false},{"option":"Facial vein communicates with cavernous sinus through inferior ophthalmic vein","bool":true},{"option":"Drains into the maxillary vein","bool":false},{"option":"Connects with cavernous sinus through emissary veins","bool":false},{"option":"Communicates with facial vein by deep facial vein","bool":false}],"id":147},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which sinus is the most common site for thrombosis?","answers":[{"option":"Cavernous","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenoidal","bool":false},{"option":"Superior sagittal","bool":true}],"id":148},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Where does the parotid duct open into the oral cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Maxillary teeth near 2nd molar","bool":true},{"option":"Mandibular teeth near 3rd premolar","bool":false},{"option":"Mandibular teeth near 2nd molar","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary teeth near 2nd premolar","bool":false},{"option":"Mandibular teeth near 2nd premolar","bool":false}],"id":149},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which of the following statements is not true for the tongue mucosa?","answers":[{"option":"The muscle fibers are arranged in all directions","bool":false},{"option":"The surface is not firmly attached to the muscles","bool":true},{"option":"The lower border of tongue is smooth with typical lining mucosa","bool":false},{"option":"Tongue is a striated muscle covered by mucosa","bool":false},{"option":"Elevations of mucous membrane are called lingual papillae","bool":false}],"id":150},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which of the following two veins join to form the retromandibular vein?","answers":[{"option":"Superficial temporal and maxillary","bool":true},{"option":"Supratrochlear and supraorbital","bool":false},{"option":"Superior and inferior labial","bool":false},{"option":"Angular and inferior labial","bool":false},{"option":"Superior ophthalmic and facial","bool":false}],"id":151},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which of the following muscles causes the opening of the mouth?","answers":[{"option":"Sternohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Omohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Sternothyroid","bool":false},{"option":"Thyrohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Digastric","bool":true}],"id":152},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is not caused by meperidine?","answers":[{"option":"Euphoria","bool":false},{"option":"Seizures","bool":false},{"option":"Analgesia","bool":false},{"option":"Miosis","bool":true},{"option":"Mydriasis","bool":false}],"id":153},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"At what somite stage does the cranial neuropore close?","answers":[{"option":"6-10 somite stage","bool":false},{"option":"0-2 somite stage","bool":false},{"option":"14-18 somite stage","bool":false},{"option":"18-20 somite stage","bool":true},{"option":"10-14 somite stage","bool":false}],"id":154},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which of the following nerves innervates the palatine tonsils?","answers":[{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoglossal nerve","bool":false}],"id":155},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"The olfactory epithelium is present in which part of the nasal cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Medial","bool":false},{"option":"Superior","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior","bool":false}],"id":156},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which of the following muscles is supplied by two different nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Stylohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Sternohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Sternothyroid","bool":false},{"option":"Digastric","bool":true},{"option":"Mylohyoid","bool":false}],"id":157},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is not a branch of the maxillary nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Supraorbital nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Zygomaticotemporal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Pharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Infraorbital nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Nasopalatine nerve","bool":false}],"id":158},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which of the following nerves supplies sternocleidomastoid muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Glossopharyngeal","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus","bool":false},{"option":"Axillary","bool":false},{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory","bool":true}],"id":159},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"The internal jugular vein is a continuation of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Petrosal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Sigmoid sinus","bool":true},{"option":"Cavernous sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Confluence of sinuses","bool":false}],"id":160},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which of the following foramina connects the infratemporal fossa to the middle cranial fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Foramen ovale","bool":true},{"option":"Foramen magnum","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen lacerum","bool":false},{"option":"Jugular foramen","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false}],"id":161},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"The loss of heterozygosity (LOH) mutation at 17p causes dysplasia transformation. This involves which gene?","answers":[{"option":"Rb","bool":false},{"option":"pTEN","bool":false},{"option":"p53","bool":true},{"option":"p16","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false}],"id":162},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which of the following structures passes through incisive fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Ophthalmic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Chorda tympani","bool":false},{"option":"Superior alveolar nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Nasopalatine nerve","bool":true}],"id":163},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Vitamin A is involved in which of the following process?","answers":[{"option":"Breakdown of rhodopsin","bool":false},{"option":"Resynthesis of rhodopsin","bool":false},{"option":"Synthesis of rhodopsin","bool":true},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Storage of iodopsin","bool":false}],"id":164},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which of the following enzymes is involved in the conversion of retinol to retinal?","answers":[{"option":"Retinol translocase","bool":false},{"option":"Retinol dehydrogenase in presence of NAD","bool":true},{"option":"Retinol synthase","bool":false},{"option":"Retinol oxidase","bool":false},{"option":"Retinol isomerase","bool":false}],"id":165},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is defined by the visual area seen by an eye at a given instant?","answers":[{"option":"Sight","bool":false},{"option":"Myopia","bool":false},{"option":"Hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Field of vision","bool":true},{"option":"Angle of vision","bool":false}],"id":166},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"The roof of the posterior triangle of the neck is formed by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Superficial fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Investing layer of deep cervical fascia","bool":true},{"option":"Prevertebral layer of deep cervical fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Subcutaneous tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Platysma","bool":false}],"id":167},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which of these structures does not pass through the jugular foramen?","answers":[{"option":"Accessory nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Internal jugular vein","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Labyrinthine artery","bool":true},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false}],"id":168},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"What does a lesion in the right optic radiation lead to?","answers":[{"option":"Complete blindness","bool":false},{"option":"Heteronymous hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Right homonymous hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Monoccular blindness","bool":false},{"option":"Left homonymous hemianopia","bool":true}],"id":169},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which of these structures does not pass through the foramen magnum?","answers":[{"option":"Initial part of the spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoglossal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Vertebral arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior and posterior spinal arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal roots of accessory nerve","bool":false}],"id":170},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which two veins combine to form the facial vein?","answers":[{"option":"Angular and superior labial veins","bool":true},{"option":"Retromandibular and maxillary veins","bool":false},{"option":"Retromandibular and supratrochlear veins","bool":false},{"option":"Middle temporal and infratrochlear veins","bool":false},{"option":"Supraorbital and common facial veins","bool":false}],"id":171},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is the most common benign tumor of salivary glands?","answers":[{"option":"Warthin tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Adenoid cystic carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Pleomorphic adenoma","bool":true},{"option":"Sialadenitis","bool":false},{"option":"Parotid gland oncocytoma","bool":false}],"id":172},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding the skull?","answers":[{"option":"The sphenoid bone is an unpaired bone","bool":false},{"option":"Consists of 22 bones","bool":false},{"option":"The mandible is the inferior most part of the neurocranium","bool":true},{"option":"Viscerocranium is antero-inferior","bool":false},{"option":"Calvaria is dome shaped","bool":false}],"id":173},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which part does the maxillary artery NOT supply?","answers":[{"option":"Maxilla","bool":false},{"option":"Nose","bool":false},{"option":"External ear","bool":true},{"option":"Lower jaw","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral dura mater","bool":false}],"id":174},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"The lateral side of the tongue drains into which node?","answers":[{"option":"Submental nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Superior deep cervical nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Parotid nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Submandibular lymph nodes","bool":true},{"option":"Mastoid nodes","bool":false}],"id":175},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Touch and temperature sensations for the anterior 2/3rd of the tongue are supplied by what nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Hypoglossal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Mandibular branch of trigeminal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false}],"id":176},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Where are olfactory cells present?","answers":[{"option":"Conchae","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibule","bool":false},{"option":"Olfactory epithelium","bool":true},{"option":"Uncus","bool":false}],"id":177},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"The corneal epithelium consists of which cell type?","answers":[{"option":"Simple columnar cells","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous non-keratinized cells","bool":true},{"option":"Transitional cells","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous keratinized cells","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified columnar cells","bool":false}],"id":178},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Middle conchae is part of which bone?","answers":[{"option":"Temporal","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenoid","bool":false},{"option":"Ethmoid","bool":true},{"option":"Frontal","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal","bool":false}],"id":179},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which structure is not attached to styloid process?","answers":[{"option":"Stylohyoid muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Stylopharyngeus muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Stylomandibular ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Styloglossus muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenomandibular ligament","bool":true}],"id":180},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"What is the point of intersection of the lambdoid and sagittal sutures?","answers":[{"option":"Pterion","bool":false},{"option":"Nasion","bool":false},{"option":"Lambda","bool":true},{"option":"Asterion","bool":false},{"option":"Bregma","bool":false}],"id":181},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"What is the H-shaped suture on the lateral side of the skull called?","answers":[{"option":"Pterion","bool":true},{"option":"Inion","bool":false},{"option":"Bregma","bool":false},{"option":"Lambda","bool":false},{"option":"Asterion","bool":false}],"id":182},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"The maxillary sinus drains into which structure?","answers":[{"option":"Superior nasal meatus","bool":false},{"option":"Middle nasal meatus","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior nasal meatus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior conchae","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior conchae","bool":false}],"id":183},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"What of the following structures does not pass through the carotid sheath?","answers":[{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Internal carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Common carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"External carotid artery","bool":true},{"option":"Internal jugular vein","bool":false}],"id":184},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which fascia of the neck divides into two to cover the sternocleidomastoid and trapezius muscles?","answers":[{"option":"Prevertebral layer","bool":false},{"option":"Investing layer","bool":true},{"option":"Superficial cervical fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Carotid sheath","bool":false},{"option":"Pretracheal layer","bool":false}],"id":185},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Low pitch sound is detected by which structure?","answers":[{"option":"Semicircular canals","bool":false},{"option":"Auricle","bool":false},{"option":"Helicotrema","bool":true},{"option":"Cochlea","bool":false},{"option":"Utricle","bool":false}],"id":186},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Astigmatism is caused due to curvature loss of which structure?","answers":[{"option":"Retina","bool":false},{"option":"Eye brows","bool":false},{"option":"Iris","bool":false},{"option":"Lens","bool":true},{"option":"Pupil","bool":false}],"id":187},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"A person has pain near the angle of the mandible and is not able to close his mouth due to spasm of a muscle. What is this muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Platysma","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral pterygoid","bool":false},{"option":"Medial pterygoid","bool":true},{"option":"Digastric","bool":false},{"option":"Geniohyoid","bool":false}],"id":188},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"What is the point of junction of the coronal and sagittal sutures?","answers":[{"option":"Pterion","bool":false},{"option":"Asterion","bool":false},{"option":"Inion","bool":false},{"option":"Lambda","bool":false},{"option":"Bregma","bool":true}],"id":189},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"A person has right eye blindness. When light is shown on his left eye, what will be the pupillary response?","answers":[{"option":"Only the left pupil will constrict","bool":false},{"option":"No response","bool":false},{"option":"Both pupils will constrict","bool":true},{"option":"Both pupils will dilate","bool":false},{"option":"Closure of eye lids","bool":false}],"id":190},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"A person has right eye blindness. When a light is shined on his right eye, what will be the pupillary response?","answers":[{"option":"Both pupils will constrict","bool":false},{"option":"Only the left pupil will constrict","bool":false},{"option":"No response","bool":true},{"option":"Closure of eye lids","bool":false},{"option":"Both pupils will dilate","bool":false}],"id":191},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"What nerves are affected in jugular foramen syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"CN 10, 11 and 12","bool":false},{"option":"CN 9, 10 and 11","bool":true},{"option":"CN 8, 9 and 10","bool":false},{"option":"CN 7, 8 and 10","bool":false},{"option":"CN 7, 8 and 9","bool":false}],"id":192},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is not part of the temporal bone?","answers":[{"option":"Tympanic part","bool":false},{"option":"Petromastoid part","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal part","bool":true},{"option":"Zygomatic part","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous part","bool":false}],"id":193},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Anything that might be taken into the nose accidentally goes into the pharynx through what structure?","answers":[{"option":"Nasopharynx","bool":true},{"option":"Eustachian tube","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal vestibules","bool":false},{"option":"Meatus","bool":false},{"option":"Conchae","bool":false}],"id":194},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is the best initial imaging modality for diagnosing a thyroglossal duct cyst?","answers":[{"option":"CT scan","bool":false},{"option":"MRI scan","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound","bool":true},{"option":"PET scan","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray","bool":false}],"id":195},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"What does the cartilage of the 3rd pharyngeal arch develop into?","answers":[{"option":"Greater horn of hyoid bone","bool":true},{"option":"Patella","bool":false},{"option":"Styloid process","bool":false},{"option":"Lesser horn of hyoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"Outer ear","bool":false}],"id":196},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"When the eye is medially rotated, what muscle is the prime depressor of the eyeball?","answers":[{"option":"Superior oblique","bool":true},{"option":"Medial rectus","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior oblique","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral rectus","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior rectus","bool":false}],"id":197},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"What nerve is the closest to the styloid process within the carotid sheath?","answers":[{"option":"Hypoglossal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":true}],"id":198},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"Which of the following fibers connect the Edinger-Westphal nucleus to short ciliary nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Postsynaptic sympathetic fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Presynaptic sympathetic fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Postsynaptic parasympathetic fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Presynaptic parasympathetic fibers","bool":true},{"option":"Somatic efferent fibers","bool":false}],"id":199},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"Which of the following is true regarding the sternocleidomastoid muscle?","answers":[{"option":"When one side acts alone, the head moves downward","bool":false},{"option":"Forms floor of posterior triangle of neck","bool":false},{"option":"Covers cervical plexus posteriorly","bool":true},{"option":"Forms floor of the anterior triangle of the neck","bool":false},{"option":"It is innervated only by the accessory nerve","bool":false}],"id":200},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"Which of the following is true regarding nerves of the cervical plexus?","answers":[{"option":"Suboccipital nerve is purely a sensory nerve","bool":false},{"option":"The C4 anterior rami forms ansa cervicalis","bool":false},{"option":"The lesser occipital nerve supplies the anterior part of the ear","bool":false},{"option":"The C2 posterior rami forms greats occipital nerve","bool":false},{"option":"The C3 anterior rami contributes to the inferior root of the ansa cervicalis","bool":true}],"id":201},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"What is true regarding the temporomandibular joint?","answers":[{"option":"Masseteric nerve lies posterior to the joint","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior fibers of the temporalis muscle help in retraction","bool":false},{"option":"Protrusion occurs at the lower compartment of joint","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral movements take place in the vertical axis","bool":true},{"option":"The lateral pterygoid muscle retracts the mandible","bool":false}],"id":202},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"What is the normal visual acuity?","answers":[{"option":"12/6","bool":false},{"option":"20/6","bool":false},{"option":"6/6","bool":true},{"option":"6/5","bool":false},{"option":"30/20","bool":false}],"id":203},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"In the equation V=d/D used for visual acuity, what does 'd' stand for?","answers":[{"option":"Distance between the subject's two eyes","bool":false},{"option":"Distance between the subject and the doctor","bool":false},{"option":"Distance between the doctor and the Snellen's chart","bool":false},{"option":"Distance between the subject and Snellen's chart","bool":true},{"option":"Distance between the subject and the subject's romantic interest","bool":false}],"id":204},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"What is the normal distance required between the subject and Snellen's chart to read it?","answers":[{"option":"12 meters","bool":false},{"option":"3 meters","bool":false},{"option":"6 meters","bool":true},{"option":"1 meter","bool":false},{"option":"9 meters","bool":false}],"id":205},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"What area(s) can we place the tuning fork on to perform the Weber's test?","answers":[{"option":"Middle of the scalp only","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Under the nose only","bool":false},{"option":"The middle of the forehead only","bool":false}],"id":206},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"What distance is required between the ear and the tuning fork to check air conduction in the Rinne test?","answers":[{"option":"3-5cm","bool":false},{"option":"5-6cm","bool":false},{"option":"4-5cm","bool":false},{"option":"9-10cm","bool":false},{"option":"1-2cm","bool":true}],"id":207},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"What is the normal range of intelligence quotient (IQ)?","answers":[{"option":"50-70","bool":false},{"option":"70-90","bool":false},{"option":"130-150","bool":false},{"option":"180-200","bool":false},{"option":"90-110","bool":true}],"id":208},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"What does distichiasis mean?","answers":[{"option":"Misdirected eyelashes","bool":false},{"option":"Outward protrusion of eyelid","bool":false},{"option":"Excessive sweating","bool":false},{"option":"Downward drooping of upper eyelid","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory row of eyelashes","bool":true}],"id":209},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"What is a fixation point used for?","answers":[{"option":"All of these","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"To immobilise the eye","bool":false},{"option":"To examine the pupil","bool":false},{"option":"To restrict eyeball movement","bool":false}],"id":210},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"Conductive deafness is caused by what?","answers":[{"option":"Defect in neural pathway","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of eight cranial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Impaired sound transmission through the auditory canal","bool":true},{"option":"Defect in vestibule","bool":false}],"id":211},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"What structure is devoid of rods and cones?","answers":[{"option":"Neural layer","bool":false},{"option":"Optic disc","bool":true},{"option":"Fovea centralis","bool":false},{"option":"Macula lutea","bool":false},{"option":"Retina","bool":false}],"id":212},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"What embryological structure is the major source of the eyeball?","answers":[{"option":"Lens placode","bool":false},{"option":"Optic cup","bool":true},{"option":"Otic placode","bool":false},{"option":"Neural crest cells","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":213},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"The primary palate is derived from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Otic placode","bool":false},{"option":"Hypobranchial eminence","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary prominences","bool":false},{"option":"Two palatine shelves","bool":false},{"option":"Intermaxillary segment","bool":true}],"id":214},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"Which cell may cause excitation or inhibition in the retina?","answers":[{"option":"Ganglionic cells","bool":false},{"option":"Bipolar cells","bool":true},{"option":"Cones","bool":false},{"option":"Horizontal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Rods","bool":false}],"id":215},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"What area of the retina contains no rods?","answers":[{"option":"Outer nuclear layer","bool":false},{"option":"Macula","bool":false},{"option":"Granular layer","bool":false},{"option":"Fovea centralis","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":216},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"What bony area has an H-shaped suture adjoining four skull bones?","answers":[{"option":"Lambda","bool":false},{"option":"Pterion","bool":true},{"option":"Asterion","bool":false},{"option":"Nasion","bool":false},{"option":"Glabella","bool":false}],"id":217},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"A 35-year old woman presented to the clinic with a gradually growing nodule on her face. On physical examination, a 3cm nodular, non-tender, mobile mass is palpable on the left side of the face anterior to the area and just superior to the mandible. The biopsy of the nodule reveals ductal epithelial and myoepithelial cells along with cartilage in a myxoid stroma. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Acinic cell tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Burkitt lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Pleomorphic adenoma","bool":true},{"option":"Mucoepidermoid carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":false}],"id":218},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"The hearing receptors are found on what membrane?","answers":[{"option":"Tectorial membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Basilar membrane","bool":true},{"option":"Tentorial membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Spiral membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibular membrane","bool":false}],"id":219},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"The endolymph is found in what compartment?","answers":[{"option":"Scala tympani","bool":false},{"option":"Scala media","bool":true},{"option":"Middle ear cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Ductus reunions","bool":false},{"option":"Scala vestibuli","bool":false}],"id":220},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"Which of the following is true about the second pharyngeal arch?","answers":[{"option":"Gives rise to the malleus and incus","bool":false},{"option":"Contributes to the epithelium of the dorsum of tongue","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Gives rise to muscles of facial expression","bool":true},{"option":"Forms the greater horn of the hyoid bone","bool":false}],"id":221},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"Which of the following is not an error of refraction?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Myopia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypermetropia","bool":false},{"option":"Presbyopia","bool":false},{"option":"Emmetropia","bool":true}],"id":222},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"What statement is incorrect regarding the human eye?","answers":[{"option":"Photopic vision is the main function of cones","bool":false},{"option":"Contains fovea centralis fully packed with cones","bool":false},{"option":"Responds only to light of wavelength 600-750nm","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Scotopic vision is the main function of rods","bool":false}],"id":223},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"What structure does not act as a refractory medium for the eye?","answers":[{"option":"Vitreous humour","bool":false},{"option":"Aqueous humour","bool":false},{"option":"Cornea","bool":false},{"option":"Retina","bool":false},{"option":"Pupil","bool":true}],"id":224},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"What statement is false regarding the sense of taste?","answers":[{"option":"Is lost in aguesia","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Is maximum for salty sensation","bool":true},{"option":"Is a chemical sense","bool":false},{"option":"Is called gustation","bool":false}],"id":225},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"What statement is false regarding photopic vision?","answers":[{"option":"It is mediated by cones","bool":false},{"option":"It does not use rhodopsin","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"It helps you see in the dark","bool":true},{"option":"It produces an image of fine resolution","bool":false}],"id":226},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"A 35-year old female presented with dizziness for one day. She has a sense of rotation of the surrounding, most marked when lying on the left side. The Dix Hallipke maneuver is performed, with the patient asked to sit at the edge of the bed, moving her head 45 degrees on the left side, and then making her lie down with her head 30 degrees downwards. What will you observe to declare the test positive for benign positional vertigo?","answers":[{"option":"Gaze palsy","bool":false},{"option":"Nystagmus","bool":true},{"option":"Ptosis","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Hearing loss","bool":false}],"id":227},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"What can cause xeropthalmia?","answers":[{"option":"Conjunctival inflammation","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased keratinization of skin","bool":false},{"option":"Keratinization of cornea","bool":true},{"option":"Pleomorphic adenoma","bool":false},{"option":"Corneal infection","bool":false}],"id":228},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"What area of the retina is most concerned with the acuity of vision?","answers":[{"option":"Blind spot","bool":false},{"option":"Fovea centralis","bool":true},{"option":"Conjunctiva","bool":false},{"option":"Macula","bool":false},{"option":"Periphery of retina","bool":false}],"id":229},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"Night blindness is associated with abnormality in what cells?","answers":[{"option":"Ganglion cells","bool":false},{"option":"Bipolar cells","bool":false},{"option":"Amacrine cells","bool":false},{"option":"Rods","bool":true},{"option":"Cones","bool":false},{"option":"Horizontal cells","bool":false}],"id":230},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"Which of the following angle is widest in the direction in the visual field?","answers":[{"option":"Upwards","bool":false},{"option":"Downwards","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Temporal","bool":true},{"option":"Nasal","bool":false}],"id":231},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"Which of the following are photoreceptors of the retina of the eye?","answers":[{"option":"Melanocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Rods","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Rods and cones","bool":true},{"option":"Cones","bool":false}],"id":232},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"A 57-year-old man with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) presents to the outpatient department with complaints of dysphagia. On examination, a whitish pseudomembranous was seen on the oropharynx and tongue. This pseudomembrane was scraped off when it tried to scrape it. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Oral candidiasis","bool":true},{"option":"Erythroplakia","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes labialis","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Leukoplakia","bool":false}],"id":233},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"The light entering the eye passes to which layer of the retina first?","answers":[{"option":"Pigmented layer","bool":false},{"option":"Ganglionic cell layer","bool":true},{"option":"Bipolar layer","bool":false},{"option":"Inner plexiform layer","bool":false},{"option":"Receptor cell layer","bool":false}],"id":234},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"What structure forms the lateral wall of the infratemporal fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior surface of the maxilla","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral pterygoid plate","bool":false},{"option":"External acoustic meatus","bool":false},{"option":"Zygomatic arch","bool":false},{"option":"Ramus of mandible","bool":true}],"id":235},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"Which of the following structures is not crossed by light when entering the eye?","answers":[{"option":"Aqueous humor","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false},{"option":"Cornea","bool":false},{"option":"Lens","bool":false},{"option":"Ciliary process","bool":true}],"id":236},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"The most common cause of blindness in diabetes is due to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Corneal opacity","bool":false},{"option":"Conjunctivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Retinopathy","bool":true},{"option":"Lens dislocation","bool":false},{"option":"Glaucoma","bool":false}],"id":237},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"Union of what structures form the medial orbital margin?","answers":[{"option":"Lacrimal and zygomatic bone","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal and zygomatic bone","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal and maxillary bone","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal and maxillary bone","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":238},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"The body (anterior two-thirds) of the tongue is developed from what structure?","answers":[{"option":"Hypobranchial eminence","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculum impar","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral lingual swellings","bool":true},{"option":"Copula","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":239},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"Visual impairment in diabetes is due to all of the following except:","answers":[{"option":"Damage to the rods","bool":true},{"option":"Occlusion of retinal arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Cataract at an early age","bool":false},{"option":"Retinal detachment","bool":false},{"option":"Neovascularization","bool":false}],"id":240},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"The site of union between the primary and secondary palate is identified as what in the adult?","answers":[{"option":"Uvula","bool":false},{"option":"Median palatal raphe","bool":false},{"option":"Passavant's ridge","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen cecum","bool":false},{"option":"Incisive foramen","bool":true}],"id":241},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"Which of the following is involved in rotational acceleration?","answers":[{"option":"Macula","bool":false},{"option":"Cristae ampularis","bool":true},{"option":"Saccule","bool":false},{"option":"Organ of corti","bool":false},{"option":"Utricle","bool":false}],"id":242},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"The middle ear cavity develops from what structure?","answers":[{"option":"First pharyngeal pouch","bool":true},{"option":"First pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"Auditory vesicle","bool":false},{"option":"Second pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"First pharyngeal cleft","bool":false}],"id":243},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"Ligation of what artery will relieve chronic nose bleeds?","answers":[{"option":"Sphenopalatine artery","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior ethmoidal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior ethmoidal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Facial artery","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":244},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"Which of the following is involved in hearing?","answers":[{"option":"Saccule","bool":false},{"option":"Semicircular canal","bool":false},{"option":"Cochlea","bool":true},{"option":"Utricle","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false}],"id":245},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"What is true about the chorda tympani nerve?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Supplies the parotid gland","bool":false},{"option":"Contain postganglionic parasympathetic fibres","bool":false},{"option":"Joins lingual nerve in the infratemporal fossa","bool":true},{"option":"Is a branch of glossopharnygeal nerve","bool":false}],"id":246},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"Dry eyes result from a lesion at which one of the following ganglions?","answers":[{"option":"Superior cervical","bool":false},{"option":"Pterygopalatine","bool":true},{"option":"Otic","bool":false},{"option":"Ciliary","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenopalatine","bool":false}],"id":247},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"All of the following muscles are supplied by the hypoglossal nerve except which?","answers":[{"option":"Thyrohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Palatoglossus","bool":true},{"option":"Genioglossus","bool":false},{"option":"Geniohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"All of these are supplied by hypoglossal","bool":false}],"id":248},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"Which of the following is correct regarding the cochlea?","answers":[{"option":"Has helicotrema at base","bool":false},{"option":"Tectorial membrane forms basal lamina of hair cells","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Reissner's membrane lies towards the scala vestibuli","bool":true},{"option":"Contains maculae","bool":false}],"id":249},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"Which of the following statements is incorrect, if any, about neuroepithelium?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"These are specialized cells for the reception of taste","bool":false},{"option":"It forms nasal mucosa","bool":false},{"option":"It is simple cuboidal epithelium","bool":true},{"option":"It is present in cochlea","bool":false}],"id":250},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"Which of the following types of papillae does not contain tastebuds?","answers":[{"option":"Filliform","bool":true},{"option":"Circumvallate","bool":false},{"option":"Fungiform","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Foliate","bool":false}],"id":251},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2018"],"question":"Which of the following is true about the venous drainage of the face?","answers":[{"option":"The pterygoid venous plexus does not drain to the maxillary vein","bool":false},{"option":"Deep facial veins drains into the pterygoid plexus","bool":true},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"The sphenopalatine, deep temporal, masseteric, and buccal veins are not the tributaries of the pterygoid venous plexus","bool":false},{"option":"The pterygoid plexus does not drain the nasal cavity and paranasal sinuses","bool":false}],"id":252},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Chewing of tobacco leads to oral cancer mostly in:","answers":[{"option":"North America","bool":false},{"option":"China","bool":false},{"option":"India","bool":true},{"option":"South America","bool":false},{"option":"Bangladesh","bool":false}],"id":253},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Anterior fontanelle closes at what age?","answers":[{"option":"4 to 5 months","bool":false},{"option":"1 to 2 months","bool":false},{"option":"After 2 years","bool":false},{"option":"6 to 7 years","bool":false},{"option":"9 to 18 months","bool":true}],"id":254},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which of the following muscles contributes to palatine aponeurosis?","answers":[{"option":"Palatopharyngeus","bool":false},{"option":"Tensor veli palatini","bool":true},{"option":"Palatoglossus","bool":false},{"option":"Genioglossus","bool":false},{"option":"Stylopharyngeus","bool":false}],"id":255},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is not a characteristic feature of circumvallate papillae?","answers":[{"option":"Mucous secretions are in the grooves around them","bool":true},{"option":"They are supplied by the glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"They are 8-12 in number","bool":false},{"option":"They are largest papillae","bool":false},{"option":"They are surrounded by grooves","bool":false}],"id":256},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Bell palsy involves the lesion of which nerve?","answers":[{"option":"7th","bool":true},{"option":"6th","bool":false},{"option":"5th","bool":false},{"option":"12th","bool":false},{"option":"3rd","bool":false}],"id":257},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which branch of the cervical plexus does not supply skin?","answers":[{"option":"Transverse cervical nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Supraclavicular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Branches from C1","bool":true},{"option":"Lesser occipital nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Greater auricular nerve","bool":false}],"id":258},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"A student is concerned about a muscle in the neck which is related to the borders of both anterior and posterior triangles. Which muscle is this?","answers":[{"option":"Trapezius","bool":false},{"option":"Omohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Digastric","bool":false},{"option":"Rectus capitis","bool":false},{"option":"Sternocleidomastoid","bool":true}],"id":259},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"A young patient presents to the outpatient department with an ulcer on the tongue. Which of the following lymph nodes will most likely be enlarged?","answers":[{"option":"Deep cervical","bool":false},{"option":"Jugulo-omyhoid","bool":true},{"option":"Jugulodigastric","bool":false},{"option":"Parotid","bool":false},{"option":"Supraclavicular","bool":false}],"id":260},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Where is the primary auditory cortex located?","answers":[{"option":"Occipital lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Temporal lobe","bool":true},{"option":"Parietal lobe","bool":false}],"id":261},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Deflection of the stereocilia away from the kinocilium in the cochlea causes which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Closing of potassium channels","bool":true},{"option":"Opening of sodium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Closing of sodium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Closing of sodium-chloride channels","bool":false},{"option":"Opening of chloride channels","bool":false}],"id":262},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"A patient presents with his right eye deviated down and out. On examination, there is a double vision on moving the eye to the right. Which nerve is damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Right trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Right oculomotor nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Left trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Left oculomotor nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Right ophthalmic nerve","bool":false}],"id":263},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"The vestibular nucleus helps maintain body balance through connections with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":true},{"option":"Occipital lobe","bool":false}],"id":264},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"The intrinsic muscles of the larynx are derivatives of which pharyngeal arch?","answers":[{"option":"6th","bool":true},{"option":"4th","bool":false},{"option":"1st","bool":false},{"option":"3rd","bool":false},{"option":"2nd","bool":false}],"id":265},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Boundaries of the pyriform aperture are formed by which of the following bones?","answers":[{"option":"Maxillary and zygomatic","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal and maxillary","bool":true},{"option":"Frontal and maxillary","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal and frontal","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary and sphenoid","bool":false}],"id":266},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is not a branch of the facial artery?","answers":[{"option":"Superior labial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal nasal artery","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior labial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral nasal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Submental artery","bool":false}],"id":267},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"The lateral rectus muscle is supplied by which nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Oculomotor","bool":false},{"option":"Abducens","bool":true},{"option":"Maxillary","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear","bool":false},{"option":"Facial","bool":false}],"id":268},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"The carotid sinus is innervated by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Maxillary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false}],"id":269},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Extraocular muscles of the eye are chiefly supplied by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":false}],"id":270},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"The rods and cones of the retina are part of which layer?","answers":[{"option":"Inner limiting membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Inner nuclear layer","bool":false},{"option":"Outer plexiform layer","bool":false},{"option":"Outer nuclear layer","bool":true},{"option":"Inner plexiform layer","bool":false}],"id":271},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"While turning the head from side to side, like when saying \"no\", the main movement occurs at which joint?","answers":[{"option":"C7-T1","bool":false},{"option":"Atlanto-occipital joint","bool":false},{"option":"C1-C2","bool":false},{"option":"Atlanto-axial joint","bool":true},{"option":"C2-C3","bool":false}],"id":272},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is not a branch of the external carotid artery?","answers":[{"option":"Facial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenopalatine artery","bool":false},{"option":"Supraorbital artery","bool":true},{"option":"Occipital artery","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary artery","bool":false}],"id":273},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"What is the normal intraocular pressure (IOP) range?","answers":[{"option":"10-60 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"12-20 mmHg","bool":true},{"option":"5-10 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"0-5 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"10-30 mmHg","bool":false}],"id":274},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding the composition of saliva?","answers":[{"option":"Contains proteins","bool":false},{"option":"IgA antibodies secretion","bool":false},{"option":"Isotonic to plasma","bool":true},{"option":"Mostly contains water","bool":false},{"option":"Contains mucin","bool":false}],"id":275},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"A patient presented with a fracture of the middle third of the clavicle. What is the appropriate boundary of the posterior triangle formed by the fractured structure?","answers":[{"option":"Floor","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior","bool":false},{"option":"Apex","bool":false},{"option":"Base","bool":true}],"id":276},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Presence of which of the following in food results in a bitter taste?","answers":[{"option":"Aldehydes","bool":false},{"option":"Alkaloids","bool":true},{"option":"HCO3-","bool":false},{"option":"Ketones","bool":false},{"option":"H+","bool":false}],"id":277},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which veins connect the veins of the scalp to the dural venous sinuses?","answers":[{"option":"Subarachnoid veins","bool":false},{"option":"Diploic veins","bool":false},{"option":"Auricular veins","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral veins","bool":false},{"option":"Emissary veins","bool":true}],"id":278},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is not true regarding the blood supply of the face?","answers":[{"option":"External carotid artery supplies the face","bool":false},{"option":"Facial artery supplies the lacrimal sac","bool":false},{"option":"Terminal branch of facial artery anastomoses with dorsal nasal branch","bool":false},{"option":"Facial artery enters by crossing the neck of mandible","bool":true},{"option":"Supratrochlear and supraorbital arteries supply the forehead","bool":false}],"id":279},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"The sour taste of food is due to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"HCO3- ions","bool":false},{"option":"Ketones","bool":false},{"option":"Alkaloids","bool":false},{"option":"H+ ions","bool":true},{"option":"Aldehydes","bool":false}],"id":280},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which muscle is enclosed by the investing layer of the deep cervical fascia of the neck?","answers":[{"option":"Geniohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Digastric","bool":false},{"option":"Mylohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Sternocleidomastoid","bool":true},{"option":"Omohyoid","bool":false}],"id":281},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which of the following does not pass through the internal auditory meatus?","answers":[{"option":"Labyrinthine artery","bool":false},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Cochlear part of vestibulocochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibular part of vestibulocochlear nerve","bool":false}],"id":282},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which of the following communicates with the middle cranial fossa, oral cavity, nasal cavity, and orbital cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Infratemporal fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Temporal fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen spinosum","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen lacerum","bool":false},{"option":"Pterygopalatine fossa","bool":true}],"id":283},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"What is the first step in the resynthesis of rhodopsin?","answers":[{"option":"All cis retinol conversion to 11-trans retinol","bool":false},{"option":"All trans retinal conversion to 10-cis retinal","bool":false},{"option":"All trans retinol conversion to 11-cis retinol","bool":false},{"option":"All cis retinal conversion to 11-trans retinal","bool":false},{"option":"All trans retinal conversion to 11-cis retinal","bool":true}],"id":284},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"What does ageusia refer to?","answers":[{"option":"Loss of hearing","bool":false},{"option":"Partial loss of smell","bool":false},{"option":"Partial loss of taste","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of smell","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of taste","bool":true}],"id":285},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Retinol falls under which of the following functional groups?","answers":[{"option":"Ethers","bool":false},{"option":"Esters","bool":false},{"option":"Ketones","bool":false},{"option":"Alcohols","bool":true},{"option":"Aldehydes","bool":false}],"id":286},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which of the following nerve fibers form the inferior root of ansa cervicalis?","answers":[{"option":"C3 and C5","bool":false},{"option":"C1 and C3","bool":false},{"option":"C3 and C4","bool":false},{"option":"C1 and C2","bool":false},{"option":"C2 and C3","bool":true}],"id":287},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"A boy came to the outpatient department with a swelling below and at the back of the angle of the mandible. He was diagnosed with a jugulodigastric node blockage. What will be the site of pathology?","answers":[{"option":"Pharyngeal tonsils","bool":false},{"option":"Parotid gland","bool":false},{"option":"Palatine tonsils","bool":true},{"option":"Tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Pharynx","bool":false}],"id":288},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"The cerebellum is derivative of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Telencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Metencephalon","bool":true},{"option":"Diencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Myelencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Rhombencephalon","bool":false}],"id":289},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Where is the structure posterior to the pupil derived from?","answers":[{"option":"Surface ectoderm","bool":true},{"option":"Paraxial ectoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Mesoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral ectoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Neuroectoderm","bool":false}],"id":290},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Von Ebner's gland is what type of gland?","answers":[{"option":"Seromucous","bool":false},{"option":"Sebaceous glands","bool":false},{"option":"Mucous","bool":false},{"option":"Sweat glands","bool":false},{"option":"Serous","bool":true}],"id":291},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which nerve supplies muscles of facial expression?","answers":[{"option":"Mandibular","bool":false},{"option":"Facial","bool":true},{"option":"Hypoglossal","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary","bool":false},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal","bool":false}],"id":292},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"11-cis-retinal is derived from which vitamin?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin A","bool":true},{"option":"Vitamin K","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin C","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B12","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B9","bool":false}],"id":293},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"What is the composition of rhodopsin?","answers":[{"option":"opsin + 11-cis-retinal","bool":false},{"option":"scotopsin + 11-trans-retinal","bool":false},{"option":"iodopsin + 11-trans-retinal","bool":false},{"option":"scotopsin + 11-cis-retinal","bool":true},{"option":"iodopsin + 11-cis-retinal","bool":false}],"id":294},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"What equalizes pressure in the middle ear cavity and pharynx?","answers":[{"option":"Oval window","bool":false},{"option":"Eustachian tube","bool":true},{"option":"Tympanic membrane","bool":false},{"option":"External acoustic meatus","bool":false},{"option":"Auditory ossicles","bool":false}],"id":295},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is not a branch of the ophthalmic artery?","answers":[{"option":"Zygomaticofacial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Supratrochlear artery","bool":false},{"option":"Zygomaticotemporal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Infraorbital artery","bool":true},{"option":"Supraorbital artery","bool":false}],"id":296},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"What forms the lower and posterior part of the nasal septum?","answers":[{"option":"Palatine process of maxilla","bool":false},{"option":"Vomer","bool":true},{"option":"Vertical plate of ethmoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"Perpendicular plate of palatine bone","bool":false},{"option":"Body of sphenoid","bool":false}],"id":297},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Sialadenitis mostly involves the parotid gland and is caused by non-specific bacterial infection. When it involves the submandibular gland, what is the infection secondary to?","answers":[{"option":"Stone","bool":true},{"option":"Infection by staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Infection by mumps virus","bool":false},{"option":"Sjogren syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Inflammation","bool":false}],"id":298},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"What forms from the pars optica retinae?","answers":[{"option":"Ciliary body","bool":false},{"option":"Dilator pupillae muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Inner layer of the iris","bool":false},{"option":"Pigmented layer of retina","bool":false},{"option":"Sensory part of retina","bool":true}],"id":299},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is true regarding most minor salivary glands?","answers":[{"option":"They have numerous excretory units","bool":false},{"option":"They are seromucous","bool":false},{"option":"They are serous","bool":false},{"option":"They are mucous","bool":true},{"option":"They are encapsulated","bool":false}],"id":300},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"What synapses with rods and cones in the outer plexiform layer?","answers":[{"option":"Horizontal and bipolar cells","bool":true},{"option":"Bipolar cells","bool":false},{"option":"Amacrine and bipolar cells","bool":false},{"option":"Amacrine cells","bool":false},{"option":"Ganglion cells","bool":false}],"id":301},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which is the derivative of the second pharyngeal pouch?","answers":[{"option":"Lingual tonsils","bool":false},{"option":"Palatine tonsils","bool":true},{"option":"Superior parathyroid glands","bool":false},{"option":"Pharyngeal tonsils","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior parathyroid glands","bool":false}],"id":302},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which of these is not formed from the dorsal part of the otic vesicle?","answers":[{"option":"Endolymphatic duct","bool":false},{"option":"Semilunar ducts","bool":false},{"option":"Saccule","bool":true},{"option":"Utricle","bool":false},{"option":"Membranous labyrinth","bool":false}],"id":303},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Squamous papilloma is caused by which of these?","answers":[{"option":"HPV (human papilloma virus) 16 & 18","bool":false},{"option":"Coronavirus","bool":false},{"option":"EBV (Epstein-Barr virus)","bool":false},{"option":"HPV (human papilloma virus) 6 & 11","bool":true},{"option":"Adenovirus","bool":false}],"id":304},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which is the recent technique to correct myopia?","answers":[{"option":"Laser epithelial keratomileusis (LASEK)","bool":false},{"option":"Photorefractive keratectomy (PRK)","bool":false},{"option":"Radial keratotomy (RK)","bool":false},{"option":"Laser-assisted in situ keratomileusis (LASIK)","bool":true},{"option":"Conductive keratoplasty (CK)","bool":false}],"id":305},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which of the following forms the anterior boundary of the temporal fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Temporal lines and zygomatic process of zygomatic bone","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior aspect of maxilla and frontal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Zygomatic arch and zygomatic process of frontal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral pterygoid plate and frontal process of frontal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal process of zygomatic bone and zygomatic process of frontal bone","bool":true}],"id":306},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which molecules help in the depolarization of the olfactory membrane when odorant molecules combine with it?","answers":[{"option":"K+ ions","bool":false},{"option":"Ca+2 ions","bool":false},{"option":"Mg+2 ions","bool":false},{"option":"Cl- ions","bool":false},{"option":"Na+ ions","bool":true}],"id":307},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"What is found in the pterygopalatine fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Facial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Mandibular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Infraorbital nerve","bool":false},{"option":"External carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Third part of maxillary artery","bool":true}],"id":308},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"To maintain equilibrium, the vestibular nerve passes from the vestibular apparatus to which of these?","answers":[{"option":"Nucleus ambiguus","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibular nucleus and cerebellum","bool":true},{"option":"Tractus solitarius","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus gracilis","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal nucleus of trigeminal","bool":false}],"id":309},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"The auriculotemporal nerve is a branch of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Maxillary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Greater occipital nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Mandibular nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Ophthalmic nerve","bool":false}],"id":310},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"What is the term used for the dryness of the oral cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Steatorrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Sialithiosis","bool":false},{"option":"Xerostomia","bool":true},{"option":"Keratosis","bool":false},{"option":"Sialorrhea","bool":false}],"id":311},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which of the following nerves in the oral mucosa is in danger when the molar teeth and gingivae are being operated on?","answers":[{"option":"Lingual nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Mental nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior alveolar nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Nerve to lateral pterygoid","bool":false},{"option":"Buccal nerve","bool":false}],"id":312},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"During infection of the parotid gland (parotitis), pain occurs due to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Nerve compression","bool":false},{"option":"Swelling of the gland","bool":false},{"option":"Gland enlargement","bool":false},{"option":"Parotid sheath limits swelling","bool":true},{"option":"Chewing","bool":false}],"id":313},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which nonionizing modality can be used to visualize the thyroid at bedside?","answers":[{"option":"X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"CT","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray rotating envelope","bool":false},{"option":"MRI","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound","bool":true}],"id":314},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is correct regarding Von Ebner glands?","answers":[{"option":"Found on anterior 2/3rd of tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Produce serous secretions","bool":true},{"option":"Present beneath filiform papillae","bool":false},{"option":"Simple tubular glands","bool":false},{"option":"Produce mucous secretion","bool":false}],"id":315},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Where is the keratin layer present in the oral cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Lips","bool":false},{"option":"Soft palate","bool":false},{"option":"Hard palate","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar mucosa","bool":false}],"id":316},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding eyelids?","answers":[{"option":"Contain modified sweat glands called meibomian glands","bool":true},{"option":"Tarsal plates are covered by skin","bool":false},{"option":"Contain sweat glands of moll","bool":false},{"option":"Covered by layer of elastic skin","bool":false},{"option":"Lined internally by palpebral conjunctiva","bool":false}],"id":317},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which muscle is involved in forcefully closing eyelids?","answers":[{"option":"Orbital part of orbicularis occuli","bool":true},{"option":"Palpebral part of orbicularis occuli","bool":false},{"option":"Levator palpebrae superioris","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal part of orbicularis occuli","bool":false},{"option":"Procerus","bool":false}],"id":318},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"What is the most common malignant carcinoma of salivary glands?","answers":[{"option":"Warthin tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Ooncocystoma","bool":false},{"option":"Adenoid cystic carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Pleomorphic adenoma","bool":false},{"option":"Mucoepidermoid carcinoma","bool":true}],"id":319},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Nasopharyngeal carcinomas are mostly associated with which virus?","answers":[{"option":"Hepatitis B virus (HBV)","bool":false},{"option":"Epstein Barr virus (EBV)","bool":true},{"option":"Cytomegalovirus (CMV)","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatitis C virus (HCV)","bool":false},{"option":"Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)","bool":false}],"id":320},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which structures are paired correctly?","answers":[{"option":"Sphenoid process of maxilla","bool":false},{"option":"Pterygoid plate of the parietal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Styloid process of temporal bone","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior nasal spine of maxilla","bool":false},{"option":"Greater wing of frontal bone","bool":false}],"id":321},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"A young girl presents to the clinic with an infection of the auricular lobule due to wearing earrings. The infection drains to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Deep cervical nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Mastoid nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Occipital nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Parotid nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial cervical nodes","bool":true}],"id":322},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which of the following statements is correct?","answers":[{"option":"When the lens is at rest, the ciliaris muscle is contracted","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperopia can be corrected by a diverging lens","bool":false},{"option":"Emmetropia is a condition with errors in refraction","bool":false},{"option":"Lens is the major refractive component of the eye","bool":false},{"option":"Myopia can be corrected by a diverging lens","bool":true}],"id":323},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"A patient presents with raised intraocular pressure, redness of the eye, shallow anterior chamber, headache, nausea, and vomiting. Which of the following conditions is indicated?","answers":[{"option":"Open-angle glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Hyphema","bool":false},{"option":"Cataracts","bool":false},{"option":"Uveitis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute close-angle glaucoma","bool":true}],"id":324},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Excitation of photoreceptors by light leads to which changes in rhodopsin?","answers":[{"option":"Lumirhodopsin to metarhodopsin","bool":true},{"option":"Bathorhodopsin to rhodopsin","bool":false},{"option":"Metrhodopsin to bathorodopsin","bool":false},{"option":"Lumirhodopsin to bathorhodopsin","bool":false},{"option":"All-trans retinol to all-trans retinal","bool":false}],"id":325},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"The auditory ossicles which are attached to the oval window are derived from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"4nd pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"1st pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"3rd pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"2nd pharyngeal arch","bool":true}],"id":326},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Lips and palate form during which time period?","answers":[{"option":"7-8 months","bool":false},{"option":"4-5 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"5-6 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"7-8 weeks","bool":true},{"option":"4-5 months","bool":false}],"id":327},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which of these are included in the complete cleft anomaly?","answers":[{"option":"Alveolar process of maxilla + incisive fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Lip + alveolar process of maxilla + incisive fossa","bool":true},{"option":"Lip + alveolar process of maxilla","bool":false},{"option":"Lip + alveolar process of maxilla + incisive fossa on both sides","bool":false},{"option":"Lip + incisive fossa","bool":false}],"id":328},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding temporomandibular joint (TMJ)?","answers":[{"option":"All muscles are supplied by the mandibular branch of trigeminal nerve except the medial pterygoid","bool":true},{"option":"Temporalis is the primary retractor","bool":false},{"option":"All of these are correct","bool":false},{"option":"Muscles related to it are derived from 1st pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"All muscles acting at temporomandibular joint (TMJ) elevate the jaw except lateral pterygoid","bool":false}],"id":329},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which of the following occurs as a result of the blockage of the drainage of the aqueous humor?","answers":[{"option":"Coloboma","bool":false},{"option":"Amblyopia","bool":false},{"option":"Strabismus","bool":false},{"option":"Glaucoma","bool":true},{"option":"Cataract","bool":false}],"id":330},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which type of cells are olfactory receptor cells?","answers":[{"option":"Bipolar neuron","bool":true},{"option":"Unipolar neuron","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudounipolar neuron","bool":false},{"option":"Multipolar neuron","bool":false},{"option":"Nonneuronal","bool":false}],"id":331},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which technique is advised to see the extent of a mass lesion of orbit?","answers":[{"option":"MRI","bool":false},{"option":"CT scan","bool":true},{"option":"Ultrasound","bool":false},{"option":"PET scan","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral view of skull via X-ray","bool":false}],"id":332},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Along with the hypoglossal nerve, what else forms the floor of the submandibular (digastric) triangle?","answers":[{"option":"Omohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Sternothyroid","bool":false},{"option":"Sternohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Thyrohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Mylohyoid","bool":true}],"id":333},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"The external jugular vein is formed by the union of which of the following veins?","answers":[{"option":"Transverse sinus and anterior division of retromandibular","bool":false},{"option":"Sigmoid sinus and posterior division of retromandibular","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior division of retromandibular and posterior auricular","bool":true},{"option":"Maxillary and posterior auricular","bool":false},{"option":"Pterygoid and posterior auricular","bool":false}],"id":334},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which is true regarding the composition of endolymph?","answers":[{"option":"Same as extracellular fluid","bool":false},{"option":"Has a potassium concentration close to extracellular fluid","bool":false},{"option":"Same as intracellular fluid","bool":true},{"option":"Same as interstitial fluid","bool":false},{"option":"Has a sodium concentration close to extracellular fluid","bool":false}],"id":335},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which type of lens is a concave lens?","answers":[{"option":"Reflecting","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Diverging","bool":true},{"option":"Magnifying","bool":false},{"option":"Converging","bool":false}],"id":336},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which of the following muscles is not derived from the 2nd pharyngeal arch?","answers":[{"option":"Levator veli palatini","bool":true},{"option":"Buccinator","bool":false},{"option":"Stapedius","bool":false},{"option":"Stylohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior belly of digastric","bool":false}],"id":337},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding the tongue surface?","answers":[{"option":"Covered by stratified squamous epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Contains elevations called papilla","bool":false},{"option":"Contains minor salivary glands that secrete seromucous secretions","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual papillae are formed by stratified squamous epithelium only","bool":false},{"option":"Covered by stratified columnar epithelium","bool":true}],"id":338},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"All trans-retinoic acid and 9-cis-retinoic acids are responsible for which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Growth hormones","bool":false},{"option":"Iron metabolism","bool":false},{"option":"Cholesterol synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Growth and cellular differentiation","bool":true},{"option":"Bone development","bool":false}],"id":339},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is correct regarding bitot spots?","answers":[{"option":"Seen in neovascularization","bool":false},{"option":"Localized increase in thickness of cornea","bool":true},{"option":"Clouding of cornea","bool":false},{"option":"Blood in cornea","bool":false},{"option":"Seen in glaucoma","bool":false}],"id":340},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"The odorant molecule receptors are activated by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Alpha subunit","bool":false},{"option":"Ion channels","bool":false},{"option":"Tyrosine complex","bool":false},{"option":"G protein system","bool":true},{"option":"Beta subunit","bool":false}],"id":341},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"In which layer of the scalp does an infection spread easily?","answers":[{"option":"Aponeurosis","bool":false},{"option":"Periosteum","bool":false},{"option":"Skin","bool":false},{"option":"Loose connective tissue","bool":true},{"option":"Connective tissue","bool":false}],"id":342},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is correct regarding the choroid layer of the eyeball?","answers":[{"option":"It is tightly attached to the sclera","bool":false},{"option":"It has a rich nerve supply","bool":false},{"option":"It is completely avascular","bool":false},{"option":"It is located in the anterior 1/3rd of the eye","bool":false},{"option":"Its cells contain melanin pigment","bool":true}],"id":343},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is correct regarding the ciliary ganglion?","answers":[{"option":"Preganglionic sympathetic fibers synapse here","bool":false},{"option":"Postganglionic parasympathetic fibers reach eye via the short ciliary nerves","bool":true},{"option":"Postganglionic sympathetic fibers only reach the eye via short ciliary nerves","bool":false},{"option":"Postganglionic parasympathetic fibers reach the eye via long ciliary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"It is located outside the muscle cone","bool":false}],"id":344},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is correct regarding the parotid gland?","answers":[{"option":"Retromandibular vein is formed superficial to the gland","bool":false},{"option":"Its duct opens in the oral cavity opposite the second molar tooth","bool":true},{"option":"Facial nerve crosses superficial to it","bool":false},{"option":"Its duct pierces the masseter muscle on the way to oral cavity","bool":false},{"option":"It is the second largest salivary gland","bool":false}],"id":345},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"What is true regarding the pharyngeal and esophageal phases of swallowing?","answers":[{"option":"Voluntary and involuntary","bool":false},{"option":"Voluntary only","bool":false},{"option":"Respiration is inhibited","bool":false},{"option":"The esophageal phase is faster than the pharyngeal phase","bool":false},{"option":"Involuntary only","bool":true}],"id":346},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"A patient presents with a lesion of an optic tract. As a result, he is unable to see on the opposite side of the head from both eyes. This condition is called?","answers":[{"option":"Unilateral hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Unihedral hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Trihedral hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Homonymous hemianopia","bool":true},{"option":"Bitemporal hemianopia","bool":false}],"id":347},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"In a lesion at the superior orbital fissure, which structure will not be involved?","answers":[{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Ophthalmic veins","bool":false}],"id":348},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"A boy presents with difficulty in breathing and pain in the throat. Which of the following would be swollen?","answers":[{"option":"Lingual tonsils","bool":false},{"option":"Palatine tonsils","bool":false},{"option":"Pharyngeal tonsils","bool":true},{"option":"Supraclavicular tonsils","bool":false},{"option":"Cervical lymph nodes","bool":false}],"id":349},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is affected when the left side of vision of both the eyes is affected?","answers":[{"option":"Right optic tract","bool":true},{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Both optic tracts","bool":false},{"option":"Right cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral geniculate body","bool":false}],"id":350},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is the common fibrous proliferative lesion of the oral cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Erythroplakia","bool":false},{"option":"Glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Leukoplakia","bool":false},{"option":"Pyogenic granuloma","bool":false},{"option":"Fibroma","bool":true}],"id":351},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2019"],"question":"Which of the following are the eye muscles derived from?","answers":[{"option":"Trilaminar disc","bool":false},{"option":"Epimere","bool":false},{"option":"Occipital somites","bool":false},{"option":"Hypomere","bool":false},{"option":"Preotic somites","bool":true}],"id":352},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Developmentally, the cerebellum develops from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Diencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Metencephalon","bool":true},{"option":"Telencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Mesencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Myelencephalon","bool":false}],"id":353},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"The second pharyngeal pouch gives rise to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Adenoids","bool":false},{"option":"Palatine tonsil","bool":true},{"option":"Tubal tonsils","bool":false},{"option":"Pharyngeal tonsil","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual tonsil","bool":false}],"id":354},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"An 18-year-old boy has a head injury in which an immobile joint between the flat bones of the skull is disrupted. Which of the following types of joint is involved?","answers":[{"option":"Symphysis","bool":false},{"option":"Condyloid joint","bool":false},{"option":"Suture","bool":true},{"option":"Hinge joint","bool":false},{"option":"Plane joint","bool":false}],"id":355},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"A 20-year-old boy is brought to the outpatient department with a complaint of swelling below and behind the angle of the mandible. On examination, the doctor notices that it is a palpable jugulodigastric lymph node. Which of the following is the site of pathology?","answers":[{"option":"Tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Palatine tonsil","bool":true},{"option":"Cheek","bool":false},{"option":"Upper eyelid","bool":false},{"option":"Lower eyelid","bool":false}],"id":356},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"A 25-year-old woman is brought to the outpatient department with a complaint of infection (ulcer) on the tongue. Which group of lymph nodes will become enlarged?","answers":[{"option":"Jugulo-omohyoid","bool":true},{"option":"Superficial cervical","bool":false},{"option":"Occipital","bool":false},{"option":"Jugulodigastric","bool":false},{"option":"Supraclavicular","bool":false}],"id":357},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"An 8-year-old boy is brought to the outpatient department with complaints of nasal blockage and impairment of hearing. On examination, a diagnosis of adenoiditis is made due to inflammation of the tonsils. Where is the appropriate group of tonsils present?","answers":[{"option":"Nasopharynx","bool":true},{"option":"Oropharynx","bool":false},{"option":"Laryngopharynx","bool":false},{"option":"Tonsillar fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Salpingopharynx","bool":false}],"id":358},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"A patient comes to the outpatient department with a complaint of pain in the throat and impairment of hearing. Otoscopic examination reveals the blockage of the auditory tube due to the spread of infection from the pharynx. What is the appropriate site of infection in the pharynx?","answers":[{"option":"Oropharynx","bool":false},{"option":"Nasopharynx","bool":true},{"option":"Salpingopharynx","bool":false},{"option":"Palatopharynx","bool":false},{"option":"Laryngopharynx","bool":false}],"id":359},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"A patient's magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) reveals that the brain tumor is pressing on the superior orbital fissure. Which of the following structures will not be affected?","answers":[{"option":"Abducent nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Occulomotor nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Nasociliary nerve","bool":false}],"id":360},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following statement is incorrect about the retina of the eye?","answers":[{"option":"It is richly vascularized","bool":false},{"option":"It terminates anteriorly at orra serrata","bool":false},{"option":"It is the innermost layer of eye and is responsible for photoreception","bool":false},{"option":"It is easily detached from underlying choroid","bool":true},{"option":"A shallow depression called fovea is present in its posterior wall containing only cones","bool":false}],"id":361},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"The activation of the receptor by odorant particle further activates which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Alpha subunit","bool":false},{"option":"Ion channel","bool":false},{"option":"Beta subunit","bool":false},{"option":"Tyrosine complex","bool":false},{"option":"G-protein complex","bool":true}],"id":362},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Aqueous humor is secreted by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Ciliary body","bool":true},{"option":"Iris","bool":false},{"option":"Scleral glands","bool":false},{"option":"Arteries of retina","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal glands","bool":false}],"id":363},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Auditory signals are transmitted mainly by which of the following cells?","answers":[{"option":"Outer hair cells","bool":false},{"option":"Reticular lamina","bool":false},{"option":"Inner hair cells","bool":true},{"option":"Rods of Corti","bool":false},{"option":"Inner and central cells","bool":false}],"id":364},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Bending of cilia of hair cells in the organ of Corti causes which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Sodium conductance","bool":false},{"option":"Magnesium conductance","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium conductance","bool":true},{"option":"Chloride conductance","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium and sodium conductance","bool":false}],"id":365},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Bone of middle ear that covers the oval window develops from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Sixth pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"Fourth pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"Hyoid arch","bool":true},{"option":"Mandibular arch","bool":false},{"option":"Third pharyngeal arch","bool":false}],"id":366},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following bones is not involved in the formation of pterion?","answers":[{"option":"Occipital bone","bool":true},{"option":"Temporal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Parietal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenoid bone","bool":false}],"id":367},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is correct regarding parts of bones of the head and neck?","answers":[{"option":"Styloid process is a part of temporal bone","bool":true},{"option":"Parietal bone has a petrous part","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior nasal spine is a part of maxilla","bool":false},{"option":"Pterygoid process is a part of temporal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior nasal concha is a part of ethmoid bone","bool":false}],"id":368},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Considering the structure of the eyeball, which of the following is not crossed by light rays?","answers":[{"option":"Vitreous humor","bool":false},{"option":"Pupil","bool":false},{"option":"Sclera","bool":true},{"option":"Lens","bool":false},{"option":"Cornea","bool":false}],"id":369},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"The dorsal component of the auditory vesicle does not give rise to which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Semicircular canals","bool":false},{"option":"Membranous labyrinth","bool":false},{"option":"Saccule","bool":true},{"option":"Utricle","bool":false},{"option":"Endolymphatic duct","bool":false}],"id":370},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Due to the interruption of an optic tract, the field of vision on one side of each eye is affected. What is this condition called?","answers":[{"option":"Heteronymous hemianopsia","bool":false},{"option":"Bitemporal hemianopsia","bool":false},{"option":"Unilateral hemianopsia","bool":false},{"option":"Homonymous hemianopsia","bool":true},{"option":"Binasal hemianopsia","bool":false}],"id":371},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"During a discussion, a teacher says that the given fossa has communication with the middle cranial fossa, orbital cavity, oral cavity, nasal cavity, and the foramen lacerum. Which of the following fossa is being discussed?","answers":[{"option":"Infratemporal fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior cranial fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Occipital fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Temporal fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Pterygopalatine fossa","bool":true}],"id":372},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following occurs during the pharyngeal stage of swallowing?","answers":[{"option":"Vocal cords approximated and larynx is pulled upwards","bool":true},{"option":"Respiration is stimulated","bool":false},{"option":"Larynx is pulled downwards","bool":false},{"option":"Vocal cords open","bool":false},{"option":"Epiglottis moves upwards","bool":false}],"id":373},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Extraocular muscles are supplied by nerves that pass through which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Foramen ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Optic canal","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior orbital fissure","bool":false},{"option":"Superior orbital fissure","bool":true},{"option":"Foramen spinosum","bool":false}],"id":374},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is not a terminal branch of the seventh cranial nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Buccal","bool":false},{"option":"Marginal mandibular","bool":false},{"option":"Temporal","bool":false},{"option":"Ophthalmic","bool":true},{"option":"Zygomatic","bool":false}],"id":375},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Hearing loss associated with aging is termed as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Otitis media","bool":false},{"option":"Presbycusis","bool":true},{"option":"Conductive deafness","bool":false},{"option":"Sensorineural hearing loss","bool":false},{"option":"Ménière's disease","bool":false}],"id":376},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"If the head is rotated to indicate a 'no' response, the movement occurs at which of the following joint?","answers":[{"option":"Atlantooccipital joint","bool":false},{"option":"C2-C3 joint","bool":false},{"option":"C3-C4 joint","bool":false},{"option":"Atlantoaxial joint","bool":true},{"option":"C7-T1 joint","bool":false}],"id":377},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"A colorblind person, who is a protanope, lacks which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Rhodopsin","bool":false},{"option":"Green cones","bool":false},{"option":"Blue cones","bool":false},{"option":"Red cones","bool":true},{"option":"White cones","bool":false}],"id":378},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"In the process of light adaptation which of the following events occurs?","answers":[{"option":"The level of rhodopsin is high","bool":false},{"option":"Bipolar cells transmit signals at the maximum rate","bool":false},{"option":"Photochemicals in photoreceptors are reduced to retinal and opsin","bool":true},{"option":"Vitamin A is converted into retinal","bool":false},{"option":"The size of pupil is increased","bool":false}],"id":379},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"The intermediate column of the spinal cord gives rise to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Marginal layer","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior grey horn","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior grey horn","bool":false},{"option":"Mantle layer","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral grey horn","bool":true}],"id":380},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Investing layer of the deep fascia of the neck encloses which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Digastric","bool":false},{"option":"Genohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Mylohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Omohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Sternocleidomastoid","bool":true}],"id":381},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"The major site of a nose bleed is the anterior region of the medial wall of the nasal cavity. Which of the following arteries does not participate in the anastomosis at that site?","answers":[{"option":"Branches from sphenopalatine artery","bool":false},{"option":"Branches of lesser palatine artery","bool":true},{"option":"Branches of anterior ethmoidal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Branches of greater palatine artery","bool":false},{"option":"Branches from superior labial artery","bool":false}],"id":382},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"The middle ear cavity is present in which of the following bones?","answers":[{"option":"Mastoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"Temporal bone","bool":true},{"option":"Occipital bone","bool":false},{"option":"Greater wing of sphenoid","bool":false}],"id":383},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"The middle meningeal artery passes through which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Foramen ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen rotundum","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen lacerum","bool":false},{"option":"Superior orbital fissure","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen  spinosum","bool":true}],"id":384},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Most of the refraction of light occurs in the eyes at which site?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior surface of cornea","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior surface of lens","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior surface of lens","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior surface of sclera","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior surface of cornea","bool":false}],"id":385},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Cricothyroid, a muscle of the larynx develops from which of the following pharyngeal arches?","answers":[{"option":"Mandibular arch","bool":false},{"option":"Hyoid arch","bool":false},{"option":"Sixth pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"Fourth pharyngeal arch","bool":true},{"option":"Fifth pharyngeal arch","bool":false}],"id":386},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following muscles of the middle ear is supplied by the facial nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior auricular","bool":false},{"option":"Superior auricular","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior auricular","bool":false},{"option":"Stapedius","bool":true},{"option":"Tensor tympani","bool":false}],"id":387},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Nightmares occur mostly during which sleep?","answers":[{"option":"REM sleep","bool":true},{"option":"NREM -2  sleep","bool":false},{"option":"Stage of drowsiness","bool":false},{"option":"NREM -3 sleep","bool":false},{"option":"NREM -1 sleep","bool":false}],"id":388},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"The olfactory epithelium is located at which site in the nasal cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior portion of the nasal cavity","bool":false},{"option":"It is not present in the nasal cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior and lateral portion of nasal cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior and lateral portion of nasal cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Superior portion of nasal cavity","bool":true}],"id":389},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Piriform aperture is bounded by which of the following bones?","answers":[{"option":"Nasal bones and maxilla","bool":true},{"option":"Maxillary and zygomatic bones","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal and nasal bones","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal and zygomatic bones","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal and nasal bones","bool":false}],"id":390},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is true regarding the retromandibular vein?","answers":[{"option":"It is formed anterior to the ear by the union of the superficial temporal and maxillary veins","bool":true},{"option":"It joins with the common facial vein to form external jugular vein","bool":false},{"option":"It drains the side of head and superficial aspects of temporal muscles","bool":false},{"option":"It ultimately drains into internal jugular vein","bool":false},{"option":"It is formed posterior to the ear by the union of the superficial temporal and maxillary veins","bool":false}],"id":391},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following regarding mucous membrane of the tongue is incorrect?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior one third of tongue is irregular with lymphoid aggregations called lingual tonsils","bool":false},{"option":"It is firmly bound to underlying muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior two third of tongue is covered by small projections called papillae","bool":false},{"option":"It is loosely bound to underlying muscle","bool":true},{"option":"Ventral surface of tongue is covered by a smooth mucosa","bool":false}],"id":392},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is the correct change in the photochemical process occurring due to absorption of light by rhodopsin?","answers":[{"option":"All-trans retinol to all-trans retinal","bool":false},{"option":"Metarhodopsin to bathorhodopsin","bool":false},{"option":"Lumirhodopsin to metarhodopsin","bool":true},{"option":"Bathorhodopsin to rhodopsin","bool":false},{"option":"Lumirhodopsin to bathorhodopsin","bool":false}],"id":393},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is the sensory unit of the organ of Corti?","answers":[{"option":"Perilymph","bool":false},{"option":"Spiral ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Basal membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Hair cells","bool":true},{"option":"Endolymph","bool":false}],"id":394},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Taste buds of vallate papillae are most sensitive to which taste?","answers":[{"option":"Umami","bool":false},{"option":"Sour","bool":false},{"option":"Sweet","bool":false},{"option":"Salty","bool":false},{"option":"Bitter","bool":true}],"id":395},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Tensor tympani is supplied by which of the following nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Mandibular nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Vestibulocochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary nerve","bool":false}],"id":396},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following extrinsic muscles of the tongue is attached to the body of mandible?","answers":[{"option":"Hyoglossus","bool":false},{"option":"Geniohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Styloglossus","bool":false},{"option":"Palatoglossus","bool":false},{"option":"Genioglossus","bool":true}],"id":397},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"The facial primordial appearance depends on the inductive influence of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Prosencephalic organizing centre","bool":true},{"option":"Neural tube","bool":false},{"option":"Notochord","bool":false},{"option":"Mesencephalic organizing centre","bool":false},{"option":"Stomodeum","bool":false}],"id":398},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following nerve does not supply sensory innervation to the face?","answers":[{"option":"Deep temporal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Buccal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Supratrochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Supraorbital nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Zygomaticofacial nerve","bool":false}],"id":399},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following statements is true regarding the scalp?","answers":[{"option":"Wounds do not bleed easily","bool":false},{"option":"Blood vessels and nerves lie in  loose areolar tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Infections can easily spread through emissary veins into the cranial cavity","bool":true},{"option":"Wounds gape when injury is superficial to aponeurosis","bool":false},{"option":"Bleeding beneath periosteum extends through whole length of scalp","bool":false}],"id":400},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following ion is responsible for the depolarization of olfactory receptor cells after their binding with the odor molecule?","answers":[{"option":"K+ ion","bool":false},{"option":"Cl- ion","bool":false},{"option":"Na+ ion","bool":true},{"option":"H+ ion","bool":false},{"option":"Ca+2 ion","bool":false}],"id":401},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which neurotransmitter is released by rods and cones in their synapse with bipolar cells?","answers":[{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Glycine","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamate","bool":true}],"id":402},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"The primary palate forms which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Soft palate","bool":false},{"option":"Upper jaw","bool":false},{"option":"Hard palate anterior to the incisive fossa","bool":true},{"option":"Hard palate","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral palatine process","bool":false}],"id":403},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"The refractive power of the lens is expressed in which of the following units?","answers":[{"option":"Hertz","bool":false},{"option":"Diopters","bool":true},{"option":"Microns","bool":false},{"option":"Dynes","bool":false},{"option":"Decibels","bool":false}],"id":404},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"What is the relation of the retromandibular vein with the parotid gland?","answers":[{"option":"Superficial to the facial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Deep to the facial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Deep to the gland","bool":true},{"option":"Superficial to gland","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial to facial nerve","bool":false}],"id":405},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"The six extraocular muscles are supplied by which of the following nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Olfactory and oculomotor nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Abducent nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear and facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor, trochlear, and abducent nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Trigeminal and facial nerve","bool":false}],"id":406},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following structures does not originate from the utricular portion of the otic vesicle?","answers":[{"option":"Endolymphatic duct","bool":false},{"option":"Semicircular canals","bool":false},{"option":"Cochlear duct","bool":true},{"option":"Endolymphatic sac","bool":false},{"option":"Utricle","bool":false}],"id":407},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Visual pathway does not include which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Medial geniculate body","bool":true},{"option":"Cortical area 17","bool":false},{"option":"Optic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Optic chiasma","bool":false}],"id":408},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following nerves supplies the muscles of facial expression?","answers":[{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Mandibular division of trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false}],"id":409},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which one of the following structures is not a content of the posterior triangle of the neck?","answers":[{"option":"Trunks of brachial plexus","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral plexus","bool":true},{"option":"Occipital lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Subclavian artery","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory nerve","bool":false}],"id":410},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is not a branch of the maxillary division of the trigeminal nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Zygomaticofacial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Supraorbital nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Infraorbital nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior superior alveolar nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Zygomaticotemporal nerve","bool":false}],"id":411},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which primary cortical sensory area is located in the middle of the superior temporal gyrus?","answers":[{"option":"Hearing","bool":true},{"option":"Smell","bool":false},{"option":"Vision","bool":false},{"option":"Touch","bool":false},{"option":"Taste","bool":false}],"id":412},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"The infratemporal fossa communicates with the middle cranial fossa through which of the following foramen?","answers":[{"option":"Foramen ovale","bool":true},{"option":"Foramen rotundum","bool":false},{"option":"Greater palatine foramen","bool":false},{"option":"Stylomastoid foramen","bool":false},{"option":"Lesser palatine foramen","bool":false}],"id":413},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"If the lingual nerve is damaged which of the following condition is likely to occur?","answers":[{"option":"Upper gingival sensations are lost","bool":false},{"option":"Taste sensation on posterior one third of tongue is lost","bool":false},{"option":"Tongue is deviated to the left","bool":false},{"option":"Flattening of palatoglossal arch occurs","bool":false},{"option":"Submandibular secretions are lost","bool":true}],"id":414},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Vitamin A is stored in which of the following form?","answers":[{"option":"Retinyl esters","bool":true},{"option":"All trans retinoic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Retinal","bool":false},{"option":"Retinol","bool":false},{"option":"11-cis retinal","bool":false}],"id":415},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Passavant's ridge helps to close the nasopharyngeal isthmus during swallowing.Which muscle contracts to produce the passavant's ridge?","answers":[{"option":"Fibers of pharyngeal muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Upper most fibers of palatopharyngeus","bool":true},{"option":"Fibers of tensor palatini","bool":false},{"option":"Fibers of levator palatini","bool":false},{"option":"Fibers of palatoglossus","bool":false}],"id":416},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is true regarding the connections of pterygopalatine ganglion?","answers":[{"option":"Parasympathetic root is derived from deep petrosal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Secretomotor fibers from the sympathetic root supply the lacrimal gland and paranasal sinuses","bool":false},{"option":"The sensory or parasympathetic root of ganglion is formed by branches of glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Sympathetic root is derived from nerve of pterygoid canal","bool":true},{"option":"Sensory root comes from facial nerve","bool":false}],"id":417},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is the only branch coming from the medial side of the external carotid artery?","answers":[{"option":"Facial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Ascending pharyngeal artery","bool":true},{"option":"Occipital artery","bool":false},{"option":"Superior thyroid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual artery","bool":false}],"id":418},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"According to the psychoanalytic theory, what is the phenomenon that occurs if an issue or conflict in a psychosexual stage remains unresolved?","answers":[{"option":"Expressiveness","bool":false},{"option":"Fixation","bool":true},{"option":"Neuroticism","bool":false},{"option":"Regression","bool":false},{"option":"Retentiveness","bool":false}],"id":419},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following muscles contributes to the formation of the floor of the submandibular triangle along with the hyoglossus muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Omohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Thyropharyngeus","bool":false},{"option":"Mylohyoid","bool":true},{"option":"Thyrohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Sternohyoid","bool":false}],"id":420},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which spinal nerve does not have an associated dermatome?","answers":[{"option":"C5","bool":false},{"option":"C2","bool":false},{"option":"C4","bool":false},{"option":"C1","bool":true},{"option":"T1","bool":false}],"id":421},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"A 34-year-old man visits the hospital with the complaint of being unable to shrug his shoulder after an injury. Which of the following is affected?","answers":[{"option":"Jugular foramen","bool":true},{"option":"Condyloid canal","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen magnum","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoglossal canal","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior cranial foramen","bool":false}],"id":422},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"The medial nasal prominences form which of the following in the external nose?","answers":[{"option":"Dorsum of the nose","bool":false},{"option":"Apex of the nose","bool":false},{"option":"Root of the nose","bool":false},{"option":"Ala of the nose","bool":false},{"option":"Ethmoid bone","bool":true}],"id":423},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"An infection of the eustachian tube causes which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Acute mastoiditis","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibular neuronitis","bool":false},{"option":"Presbycusis","bool":false},{"option":"Otitis media","bool":true},{"option":"Otitis externa","bool":false}],"id":424},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Activation of receptor by an odorant particle is by what mechanism?","answers":[{"option":"PI3 kinase","bool":false},{"option":"G protein complex","bool":true},{"option":"Ion channel","bool":false},{"option":"β subunit","bool":false},{"option":"Tyrosine complex","bool":false}],"id":425},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"A lesion of the oculomotor nerve result in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Esotropia","bool":false},{"option":"Pupillary contriction","bool":false},{"option":"Exotropia","bool":true},{"option":"Ciliary muscle spasm","bool":false},{"option":"Myopia","bool":false}],"id":426},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following does not supply the subcutaneous structures?","answers":[{"option":"C2","bool":false},{"option":"C4","bool":false},{"option":"C5","bool":false},{"option":"C3","bool":false},{"option":"C1","bool":true}],"id":427},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following papillae are damaged if there is damage to the tongue anterior to the terminal sulcus?","answers":[{"option":"Foliate","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual","bool":false},{"option":"Fungiform","bool":false},{"option":"Circumvallate","bool":true},{"option":"Filiform","bool":false}],"id":428},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"In which region are cristae found?","answers":[{"option":"Eustachian tube","bool":false},{"option":"Cochlea","bool":false},{"option":"Semicircular duct","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Tympanic cavity","bool":false}],"id":429},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"The stereocilia of the hair cells of the organ of Corti are embedded in?","answers":[{"option":"Basilar membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Tympanic membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Tectorial membrane","bool":true},{"option":"Otolithic membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Reissner membrane","bool":false}],"id":430},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Prevertebral fascia forms the floor of which triangle?","answers":[{"option":"Muscular triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Omohyoid trianlge","bool":false},{"option":"Carotid triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Digastric triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior triangle","bool":true}],"id":431},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Through which of the following structures light doesn't pass?","answers":[{"option":"Lens","bool":false},{"option":"Vitreous body","bool":false},{"option":"Pupil","bool":false},{"option":"Cornea","bool":false},{"option":"Sclera","bool":true}],"id":432},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following statements is incorrect about the structures of the tongue?","answers":[{"option":"It has a core of skeletal muscles","bool":false},{"option":"It has lymphoid aggregates called lymphoid tonsils","bool":false},{"option":"It is lined by stratified columnar epithelium","bool":true},{"option":"It has epithelial projections called papillae","bool":false},{"option":"Seromucous glands are present in the deep part of tongue","bool":false}],"id":433},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"The pharyngeal plexus does not supply which of the following mucles?","answers":[{"option":"Stylopharyngeus","bool":true},{"option":"Middle constrictor","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior constrictor","bool":false},{"option":"Palatopharyngeus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior constrictor","bool":false}],"id":434},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Striated ducts are not present in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Parotid gland","bool":false},{"option":"Submandibular gland","bool":false},{"option":"Sublingual gland","bool":false},{"option":"Exocrine pancreas","bool":true}],"id":435},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"In phototransduction, what happens in the presence of light?","answers":[{"option":"Increase in the number of open Na+ channels","bool":false},{"option":"Increased Ca+ conductance","bool":false},{"option":"Reduced cAMP and closed Na+ channel","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased phosphodiestearse activity","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased transducin activity","bool":false}],"id":436},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"The sublingual gland produces which type of secretions?","answers":[{"option":"Predominantly serous","bool":false},{"option":"Seromucous","bool":false},{"option":"Serous","bool":false},{"option":"Mucous","bool":false},{"option":"Predominantly mucous","bool":true}],"id":437},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"What term describes the lens of the eye becoming less elastic with the passage of time?","answers":[{"option":"Anosmia","bool":false},{"option":"Aguesia","bool":false},{"option":"Presbyopia","bool":true},{"option":"Insomnia","bool":false},{"option":"Presbycusis","bool":false}],"id":438},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following nerves are not present in the posterior triangle?","answers":[{"option":"Great auricular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal part of accessory nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Transverse cervical nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Supraclavicular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Recurrent laryngeal nerve","bool":true}],"id":439},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"If the anterior 2/3rd portion of the tongue is damaged then which of the following will be lost?","answers":[{"option":"Vallate papillae","bool":false},{"option":"Filiform papillae","bool":false},{"option":"Fungiform papillae","bool":true},{"option":"Lingual papillae","bool":false},{"option":"Foliate papillae","bool":false}],"id":440},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which epithelium lines the interlobular, interlobar, and excretory duct of the lingual gland respectively?","answers":[{"option":"Stratified columnar, simple cuboidal, pseudostratified columnar","bool":false},{"option":"All three are stratified columnar","bool":false},{"option":"Simple cuboidal, simple cuboidal, stratified columnar","bool":false},{"option":"Simple cuboidal, stratified columnar, stratified columnar","bool":false},{"option":"Simple cuboidal, pseudostratified columnar, stratified columnar","bool":true}],"id":441},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"What is the hearing loss in old age termed as?","answers":[{"option":"Otitis media","bool":false},{"option":"Presbycusis","bool":true},{"option":"Vestibular neuronitis","bool":false},{"option":"Otitis sclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Labyrinthitis","bool":false}],"id":442},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which fibers are responsible for the retraction of the mandible?","answers":[{"option":"Middle fibers of temporalis","bool":false},{"option":"Masseter","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral pterygoid","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior fibers of temporalis","bool":true},{"option":"Medial pterygoid","bool":false}],"id":443},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"A man is having problems maintaining balance while rotating his head. Which of the following has the defect?","answers":[{"option":"Cochlea","bool":false},{"option":"Semicircular canals","bool":true},{"option":"Cilia","bool":false},{"option":"Eustachian tube","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibule","bool":false}],"id":444},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following forms are most easily interconvertible?","answers":[{"option":"Retinoic acid and beta-carotene","bool":false},{"option":"Retinol and retinoic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Retinal and retinoic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Retinol and retinyl esters","bool":false},{"option":"Retinal and retinol","bool":true}],"id":445},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following does not drain into the middle nasal meatus?","answers":[{"option":"Frontal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Middle ethmoidal air cells","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillay sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior ethmoidal air cells","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenoidal sinus","bool":true}],"id":446},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following statements regarding the tongue is incorrect?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral swellings merge and overlap tuberculum impar to form the anterior 2/3rd of the tongue","bool":false},{"option":"The development of tongue begins in the fourth week of embryonic life","bool":false},{"option":"The tuberculum impar eventually degenerates","bool":false},{"option":"Hypobranchial eminemce is derived from the 3rd and 4th pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"Muscles of the tongue are derived from ectoderm","bool":true}],"id":447},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is true regarding the salivary glands?","answers":[{"option":"Submandibular gland secretions are mainly mucus","bool":false},{"option":"The submandibular gland is the largest salivary gland","bool":false},{"option":"20% of salivary secretions are produced by small salivary glands","bool":false},{"option":"Parotid gland secretions are seromucous","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual gland secretions are predominantly mucus","bool":true}],"id":448},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"The contrast border in the visual image is enhanced due to the lateral inhibition of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Bipolar cells","bool":false},{"option":"Amacrine cells","bool":false},{"option":"Photoreceptors","bool":false},{"option":"Horizontal cells","bool":true},{"option":"Ganglionic cells","bool":false}],"id":449},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Hypermetropia is treated by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Concave lens","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Convex lens","bool":true},{"option":"Contact lens","bool":false},{"option":"Concavo convex lens","bool":false}],"id":450},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"A 25-year-old man comes into the outpatient department with the complaint of not being able to lift his shoulder. What is the most probable site of the lesion that is causing this?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen magnum","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen rotundum","bool":false},{"option":"Jugular foramen","bool":true}],"id":451},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Which of the following statements about the tongue is incorrect?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior two-thirds of the tongue is innervated differently from the posterior one-third","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen cecum is the site of thyroid migration","bool":false},{"option":"Musculature of the tongue is derived from ectoderm","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior two-thirds of the tongue is formed by lateral lingual swellings","bool":false},{"option":"Taste buds develop on the dorsal surface of tongue","bool":false}],"id":452},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020"],"question":"Ossification and bone formation does not occur in which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Hard palate","bool":false},{"option":"Middle ear cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Soft palate","bool":true},{"option":"Nasal septum","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral leg compartment","bool":false}],"id":453},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following structures pass through the lateral wall of the pterygopalatine fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Maxillary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Terminal branches of maxillary artery","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior alveolar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Branches of facial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Deep temporal arteries","bool":false}],"id":454},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following structures forms the anterior wall of the pterygopalatine fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior surface of maxilla","bool":true},{"option":"Zygomatic arch","bool":false},{"option":"Medial pterygoid plate","bool":false},{"option":"Infratemporal fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral pterygoid plate","bool":false}],"id":455},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which part of the mandible forms the temporomandibular joint?","answers":[{"option":"Coronoid process","bool":false},{"option":"Ramus","bool":false},{"option":"Body","bool":false},{"option":"Condylar process","bool":true},{"option":"Angle","bool":false}],"id":456},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is not a direct branch of the external carotid artery?","answers":[{"option":"Ascending pharyngeal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual artery","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenopalatine artery","bool":true},{"option":"Facial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary artery","bool":false}],"id":457},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following does not take part in the formation of the carotid sheath?","answers":[{"option":"Investing layer of fascia","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Parotid gland sheath","bool":true},{"option":"Prevertebral layer of fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Pretracheal layer of fascia","bool":false}],"id":458},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"A nerve winds around the styloid process and carries postganglionic parasympathetic fibers which stimulate salivary secretion in the submandibular and sublingual glands. What is the name of the given nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Buccal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Chorda tympani","bool":true},{"option":"Deep petrosal nerve","bool":false}],"id":459},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Maxillary sinus drains into which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior nasal meatus","bool":false},{"option":"Spheno-ethmoidal recess","bool":false},{"option":"Superior nasal meatus","bool":false},{"option":"Middle nasal meatus","bool":true},{"option":"Semilunar hiatus","bool":false}],"id":460},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"The nose has a rich vascular supply. Which of the following arteries does not directly supply the nose?","answers":[{"option":"Sphenopalatine","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior ethmoidal","bool":false},{"option":"Descending palatine","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior ethmoidal","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral nasal","bool":false}],"id":461},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"A person feels pain when drinking hot tea. On examination, the central part of the lower lip has an ulcer and associated lymph nodes are swollen. Which nodes are involved?","answers":[{"option":"Superficial cervical lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Deep cervical lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Submental nodes","bool":true},{"option":"Submandibular nodes","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":462},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Preganglionic fibers for pupillary reflex reach ciliary ganglion where they synapse and form short ciliary nerves (postganglionic fibers) that innervate the eye. Preganglionic fibers reach ciliary ganglion by which of the following nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Nasociliary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Nerve to inferior oblique","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Nerve to inferior rectus","bool":false}],"id":463},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"For near vision, the lens is accommodated to attain increased convexity. Which of the following muscle contracts to help in this action?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Iris","bool":false},{"option":"Ciliary muscle","bool":true},{"option":"Dilator pupillae","bool":false},{"option":"Sphincter pupillae","bool":false}],"id":464},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"A 20-year-old boy has an accident. In the accident, the floor of the temporal fossa is fractured. Which of the following structures is not affected?","answers":[{"option":"Squamous part of temporal  bone","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Parietal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Lesser wing of sphenoid","bool":true},{"option":"Greater wing of sphenoid","bool":false}],"id":465},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"A person meets an accident and loses all the salivary activity of the submandibular gland. The preganglionic parasympathetic secretomotor fibers to this gland are carried by which of the following nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior alveolar nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Submental nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Auriculotemporal nerve","bool":false}],"id":466},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"A patient has swelling on his face with midface mobility and malocclusion of his teeth with anterior open bite. What kind of fracture is described here/what bone is involved?","answers":[{"option":"Fracture of sphenoid body","bool":false},{"option":"Fracture of nasal bone","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Fracture of zygomatic arch","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillofacial fracture","bool":true}],"id":467},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is true about the common carotid artery?","answers":[{"option":"It supplies a branch to the thyroid gland","bool":false},{"option":"It divides into internal and external carotid artery at the upper border of thyroid cartilage","bool":true},{"option":"It has a dilatation on it just after its initiation below the bifurcation","bool":false},{"option":"At the left side, common carotid artery arises from the brachiocephalic trunk","bool":false},{"option":"At the right side, common carotid artery arises from the arch of aorta","bool":false}],"id":468},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is not a content of the pterygopalatine fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior alveolar artery","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Pterygopalatine ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Nerve to pterygoid canal","bool":false},{"option":"Zygomatic nerve","bool":false}],"id":469},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following muscles is attached to the posterior margin of the eyelid?","answers":[{"option":"Levator palpebrae superioris","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral rectus","bool":false},{"option":"Medial rectus","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Orbicularis oculi","bool":false}],"id":470},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following will not be affected by damage to the superior salivatory nucleus in the pons and facial nerve nucleus lesion?","answers":[{"option":"Stapedius","bool":false},{"option":"Mylohyoid","bool":true},{"option":"Occipito-frontalis","bool":false},{"option":"Taste sensation from anterior two thirds","bool":false},{"option":"Buccinator","bool":false}],"id":471},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Damage to the right optic tract causes a defect in which field of vision?","answers":[{"option":"Ipsilateral temporal and contralateral nasal fields","bool":false},{"option":"Ipsilateral nasal and contralateral temporal fields","bool":true},{"option":"Ipsilateral nasal and ipsilateral temporal fields","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Contralateral nasal and contralateral temporal fields","bool":false}],"id":472},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Damage to the right optic nerve will lead to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Total blindness in left eye","bool":false},{"option":"Bitemporal hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Left homonymous hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Right homonymous hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Total blindness in right eye","bool":true}],"id":473},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"A patient suffers damage to the orbit resulting in damage to the third cranial nerve. Which of the following signs will be present?","answers":[{"option":"Pupillary constriction and adduction of eye","bool":false},{"option":"Pupillary dilatation and abduction of eye","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Pupillary constriction and abduction of eye","bool":false},{"option":"Pupillary dilatation and adduction of eye","bool":false}],"id":474},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"The patient is having diplopia with restricted movements of the eye whenever he depresses or adducts the eye. Which nerve is affected?","answers":[{"option":"Sixth","bool":false},{"option":"Fourth","bool":false},{"option":"Third","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Fifth","bool":false}],"id":475},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following diseases is caused by the deficiency of vitamin A?","answers":[{"option":"Megaloblastic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Exophthalmos","bool":false},{"option":"Xerophthalmia","bool":true},{"option":"Hair loss","bool":false},{"option":"Hemorrhage","bool":false}],"id":476},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Cochlear implants are used as a treatment for which type of deafness?","answers":[{"option":"Conductive deafness","bool":false},{"option":"Sensorineural loss","bool":true},{"option":"Vestibulocochlear nerve lesion","bool":false},{"option":"Otosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":477},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"A hearing aid is most useful in which of the following hearing problems?","answers":[{"option":"Perceptive deafness","bool":false},{"option":"Noise-mediated hearing loss","bool":false},{"option":"Presbycusis","bool":false},{"option":"Sensorineural loss","bool":true},{"option":"Conductive deafness","bool":false}],"id":478},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"The greatest difference of refractive indices is found at which of the following sites?","answers":[{"option":"Between aqueous humor and the anterior surface of lens","bool":false},{"option":"Between air and anterior surface of cornea","bool":true},{"option":"Between the posterior surface of lens and vitreous humor","bool":false},{"option":"Between posterior surface of cornea and aqueous humor","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":479},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Vibrations in the cochlear fluid cause vibration in which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Basilar membrane","bool":true},{"option":"Cupula","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Tectorial membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Otolithic membrane","bool":false}],"id":480},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"A patient has sensorineural deafness in the right ear. A 'tuning fork' test will indicate which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Negative Rinne's test in left ear","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Positive Rinne's test in right ear","bool":false},{"option":"Weber's lateralized to right ear","bool":false},{"option":"Weber's lateralized to left ear","bool":true}],"id":481},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"A patient has conductive deafness in the left ear. Which of the following findings will help us know this?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Weber's lateralized to right ear","bool":false},{"option":"Positive Rinne's test in right ear","bool":false},{"option":"Positive Rinne's test in left ear","bool":false},{"option":"Weber's lateralized to left ear","bool":true}],"id":482},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"A person can not listen to low pitch sounds. Which of the following regions is involved?","answers":[{"option":"Round window","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Oval window","bool":false},{"option":"Helicotrema","bool":true},{"option":"Cochlear base","bool":false}],"id":483},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"A person takes aspirin for chest pain. He feels a very strong bitter taste. Which nerve is responsible for carrying taste sensation from the anterior two-thirds of the tongue?","answers":[{"option":"Vagus","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoglossal","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal","bool":false},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal","bool":false},{"option":"Facial","bool":true}],"id":484},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is the most sensitive part of the eye?","answers":[{"option":"Macula","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Fovea","bool":true},{"option":"Retina","bool":false},{"option":"Choroid","bool":false}],"id":485},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which part of the eye continues to grow throughout the lifetime?","answers":[{"option":"Retina","bool":false},{"option":"Lens","bool":true},{"option":"Iris","bool":false},{"option":"Choroid","bool":false},{"option":"Cornea","bool":false}],"id":486},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Optic vesicles are out pocketings formed by which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Rhombencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Diencephalon","bool":true},{"option":"Mesencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Prosencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Telencephalon","bool":false}],"id":487},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"The intermaxillary segment is formed by fusion of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Maxillary and nasal prominences","bool":false},{"option":"Medial and lateral nasal prominences","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Two lateral nasal prominences","bool":false},{"option":"Two medial nasal prominences","bool":true}],"id":488},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following structures is derived from the 1st pharyngeal arch?","answers":[{"option":"Greater cornu of hyoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Stylohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Buccinator","bool":false},{"option":"Malleus","bool":true}],"id":489},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"An infant has a cleft on the right side of the palate behind the incisive foramen. The surgeon identifies it as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Bilateral cleft of primary palate","bool":false},{"option":"Unilateral cleft of primary and posterior palate","bool":false},{"option":"Unilateral cleft of primary palate","bool":false},{"option":"Bilateral cleft of secondary palate","bool":false},{"option":"Unilateral cleft of posterior (secondary) palate","bool":true}],"id":490},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is the area of epistaxis in the nose?","answers":[{"option":"Entire nasal septum","bool":false},{"option":"Floor of nasal cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Little's area","bool":true},{"option":"Roof of nasal cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral wall of nasal cavity","bool":false}],"id":491},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following structures divides the posterior triangle of the neck into two parts?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior belly of digastric","bool":false},{"option":"Superior belly of omohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior belly of digastric","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior belly of omohyoid","bool":true},{"option":"Greater cornu of hyoid bone","bool":false}],"id":492},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following structures forms the superior border of the digastric triangle?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior belly of omohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Hyoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior belly of digastric","bool":false},{"option":"Sternocleidomastoid","bool":false},{"option":"Mandible","bool":true}],"id":493},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following structures is involved in forming the lateral border of the muscular triangle?","answers":[{"option":"Hyoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior belly of omohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Midline of the neck","bool":false},{"option":"Mandible","bool":false},{"option":"Superior belly of omohyoid","bool":true}],"id":494},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following muscles is involved in shrugging of shoulders?","answers":[{"option":"Deltoid","bool":false},{"option":"Teres major/minor","bool":false},{"option":"Pectoralis major/minor","bool":false},{"option":"Supraspinatus","bool":false},{"option":"Trapezius","bool":true}],"id":495},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"A chef adds too much salt to the soup by mistake. Which of the following is the appropriate area of the tongue which detects salty taste?","answers":[{"option":"Almost entire area of tongue ventrally","bool":false},{"option":"Back of the tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior U-shaped area of the tongue","bool":true},{"option":"Sides of the tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Tip of the tongue","bool":false}],"id":496},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"A person eats something, which is so bitter that he has to puke it out. Which of the following is the appropriate area of the tongue which detects bitter taste?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior U-shaped area of the tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Back of the tongue","bool":true},{"option":"Almost entire area of tongue ventrally","bool":false},{"option":"Tip of the tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Sides of the tongue","bool":false}],"id":497},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"A person eats something and finds it to have a delicious taste called umami. Which of the following is the appropriate area of the tongue which detects umami taste?","answers":[{"option":"Sides of the tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Almost entire area of tongue ventrally","bool":true},{"option":"Tip of the tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Back of the tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior U-shaped area of the tongue","bool":false}],"id":498},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"A man plans to lose weight so he cuts off calories and makes a salad for himself. Upon tasting it, he finds out that there is too much lemon in it. Which of the following is the appropriate area of the tongue which detects sour taste?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior U-shaped area of the tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Almost entire area of tongue ventrally","bool":false},{"option":"Tip of the tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Sides of the tongue","bool":true},{"option":"Back of the tongue","bool":false}],"id":499},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"A person eats something which is very sweet. Which of the following is the appropriate area of the tongue which detects sweet taste?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior U-shaped area of the tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Back of the tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Tip of the tongue","bool":true},{"option":"Almost entire area of tongue ventrally","bool":false},{"option":"Sides of the tongue","bool":false}],"id":500},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is true regarding the tympanic membrane?","answers":[{"option":"It consists of 2 layers","bool":false},{"option":"Footplate of stapes attaches to it","bool":false},{"option":"Malleus and incus are derived from first pharyngeal arch during embryogenesis","bool":true},{"option":"Pars flaccida is the area between the umbo of malleus and the posterior malleolar fold","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":501},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is correct regarding mastoid air cells and mastoid antrum?","answers":[{"option":"Suprameatal triangle is antero-inferior to the mastoid process","bool":false},{"option":"Mastoid air cells or antrum opens on the posterior wall of external ear","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Mastoid antrum is separated from middle cranial fossa by tegmen tympani","bool":true},{"option":"The canal for facial nerve is below the aditus to the mastoid antrum","bool":false}],"id":502},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"A friend tells you a person's number. After a few minutes, you can not recall it. This is because it has been wiped out from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Implicit memory","bool":false},{"option":"Hippocampus","bool":false},{"option":"Short-term memory","bool":true},{"option":"Long-term memory","bool":false},{"option":"Episodic memory","bool":false}],"id":503},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"11-cis retinal bound to a specific protein is classified as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Visual pigment","bool":true},{"option":"Retinoid acid binding protein","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Photo-transducer","bool":false},{"option":"Intermediates","bool":false}],"id":504},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"A 45-year-old male is diagnosed with a brain tumor that is pressing on the nerve that passes through a groove between pyramids and olives. Which of the following functions would be affected?","answers":[{"option":"Taste on the ipsilateral side of the anterior two thirds of a tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Paralysis of all the extrinsic muscles of the tongue only","bool":false},{"option":"Taste on the ipsilateral side of the posterior one third of a tongue","bool":false},{"option":"General sensations on the ipsilateral side of the anterior two thirds of a tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Paralysis of all the intrinsic muscles of the tongue","bool":true}],"id":505},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following carries a sense of temperature directly from the anterior two-thirds of a tongue to the thalamus?","answers":[{"option":"Ventro postero lateral nucleus of thalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Main sensory nucleus of trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal nucleus of trigeminal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Motor nucleus of trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Mesencephalic nucleus of trigeminal nerve","bool":false}],"id":506},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following cells of the brain detect pressure?","answers":[{"option":"Osmoreceptors","bool":true},{"option":"Ependymal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Schwann cells","bool":false},{"option":"Oligodendrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Astrocytes","bool":false}],"id":507},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"A physician found an infection involving carotid sheath. Which of the following structures might be involved?","answers":[{"option":"Ansa cervicalis","bool":false},{"option":"Common carotid artery","bool":true},{"option":"Sympathetic chain","bool":false},{"option":"External jugular vein","bool":false},{"option":"Recurrent laryngeal nerve","bool":false}],"id":508},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following sets of bones have a major contribution to the nasal septum?","answers":[{"option":"Lacrimal and sphenoidal bones","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal cartilage and nasal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Vomer and perpendicular plate of ethmoid","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior and superior nasal conchae","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary and palatine bone","bool":false}],"id":509},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following types of secretions are released into the troughs of circumvallate papillae?","answers":[{"option":"Entirely mucous from gustatory glands","bool":false},{"option":"Predominantly mucous from parotid gland","bool":false},{"option":"Entirely serous from Von Ebner's gland","bool":true},{"option":"Seromucous","bool":false},{"option":"Predominantly serous from parotid gland","bool":false}],"id":510},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following structures gives rise to the air-filled cavity present in the petrous part of the temporal bone?","answers":[{"option":"First pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"Third pharyngeal pouch","bool":false},{"option":"Second pharyngeal pouch","bool":false},{"option":"Fourth pharyngeal pouch","bool":false},{"option":"First pharyngeal pouch","bool":true}],"id":511},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"A 10-year-old boy came to the emergency department with a laceration on the tip of the chin which is bleeding. Which of the following arteries must be affected?","answers":[{"option":"Infraorbital artery","bool":false},{"option":"Mental artery","bool":true},{"option":"Buccal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary artery","bool":false},{"option":"Transverse facial artery","bool":false}],"id":512},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following lies posterior to the maxilla, inferior and deep to the zygomatic arch and ramus of the mandible?","answers":[{"option":"Middle cranial fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Mylohyoid groove","bool":false},{"option":"Temporal fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Pterygopalatine fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Infratemporal fossa","bool":true}],"id":513},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"From which view can pterygopalatine fossa be seen best?","answers":[{"option":"Norma frontalis","bool":false},{"option":"Norma occipitais","bool":false},{"option":"Norma lateralis","bool":true},{"option":"Norma basalis","bool":false},{"option":"Norma verticalis","bool":false}],"id":514},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Xeropthalmia is defined as dryness of the eye. Damage to which of the following structures can cause xeropthalmia?","answers":[{"option":"Superior cervical ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Otic ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Submandibular ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Pterygopalatine ganglion","bool":true},{"option":"Ciliary ganglion","bool":false}],"id":515},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following gives rise to the pigment epithelium layer of an eye?","answers":[{"option":"Pars iris","bool":false},{"option":"Outer layer of optic cup","bool":true},{"option":"Inner layer of optic cup","bool":false},{"option":"Pars ceca retinae","bool":false},{"option":"Pars ciliaris retinae","bool":false}],"id":516},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following muscles would be affected in case the trochlear nerve gets damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral rectus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior oblique muscle","bool":true},{"option":"Medial rectus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior rectus","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior oblique muscle","bool":false}],"id":517},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following structures does not pass through the internal acoustic meatus?","answers":[{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Vestibular division of 8th cranial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Cochlear division of 8th cranial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Labyrinthine artery","bool":false}],"id":518},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which muscle must be affected if the upper eye lid is droopy (ptosis)?","answers":[{"option":"Orbital part of orbicularis oculi","bool":false},{"option":"Palpebral part of orbicularis oculi","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior tarsus","bool":false},{"option":"Medial rectus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior rectus","bool":false}],"id":519},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Damage to which of the following structures can cause relative afferent pupillary defect (RAPD)?","answers":[{"option":"Occulomoter nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial temporal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Abducent nerve","bool":false}],"id":520},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which type of secretion is produced by the glands at the tip of the tongue?","answers":[{"option":"Purely mucous","bool":false},{"option":"gel like secretions","bool":false},{"option":"Purely serous","bool":false},{"option":"Watery secretions","bool":false},{"option":"Seromucous","bool":true}],"id":521},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Why is the temporomandibular joint, a compound condylar variety, called an atypical synovial joint?","answers":[{"option":"It is between temporal bone and mandible","bool":false},{"option":"It is highly moveable joint","bool":false},{"option":"Fibers of lateral pterygoid is are attached directly to the articular capsule","bool":false},{"option":"The articular surface is covered by fibrocartilage","bool":true},{"option":"It is a highly moveable joint but has no synovial fluid","bool":false}],"id":522},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Light can not pass from which of the following layers of the eye?","answers":[{"option":"Aqueous humor","bool":false},{"option":"Sclera","bool":true},{"option":"Vitreous humor","bool":false},{"option":"Lens","bool":false},{"option":"Pupil","bool":false}],"id":523},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following muscles would not be affected if the pharyngeal plexus, which lies deep to the middle constrictor gets damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Superior constrictor","bool":false},{"option":"Salpingopharyngeus","bool":false},{"option":"Palatopharyngeus","bool":false},{"option":"Stylopharyngeus","bool":true},{"option":"Middle constrictor","bool":false}],"id":524},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following terms is defined as the inability to see in the bright light?","answers":[{"option":"Heteropia","bool":false},{"option":"Retinitis pigmentosa","bool":false},{"option":"Xerophthalmia","bool":false},{"option":"Hemiplegia retinitis","bool":false},{"option":"Hemeralopia","bool":true}],"id":525},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Maximal movement is shown by which of the following joints when the head moves horizontally such as to say \"no\"?","answers":[{"option":"C8-T1","bool":false},{"option":"Atlanto-occipital","bool":false},{"option":"C2-C3","bool":false},{"option":"C3-C4","bool":false},{"option":"Atlanto axial","bool":true}],"id":526},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"A 7-year-old presents to the outpatient department with the complaint of difficulty in chewing and swallowing. He also complains of pain in the auricular region and external ear. After examination, the doctor finds that there is an inflammation of the parotid gland. Which of the following nerves must be irritated to cause this pain?","answers":[{"option":"Maxillary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Auriculotemporal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Buccal nerve","bool":false}],"id":527},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is an active metabolite of vitamin A present in the eye?","answers":[{"option":"Retinal","bool":true},{"option":"Beta carotene","bool":false},{"option":"Carotenoid","bool":false},{"option":"Retinoic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Retinol","bool":false}],"id":528},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following are the end products of hydrolysis of retinyl esters in intestinal mucosa?","answers":[{"option":"Retinal and retinol","bool":false},{"option":"Retinoic acid and free fatty acids","bool":false},{"option":"Retinal and free fatty acids","bool":false},{"option":"Retinoic acid and retinol","bool":false},{"option":"Retinol and free fatty acids","bool":true}],"id":529},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following muscles is attached to the articular disc of the temporomandibular joint?","answers":[{"option":"Medial pterygoid muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Temporalis","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral pterygoid muscle","bool":true},{"option":"Massetor","bool":false},{"option":"Buccinator","bool":false}],"id":530},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following muscles are involved in the formation of transverse and vertical wrinkles on the forehead?","answers":[{"option":"Corrugator supercilii and orbicularis oculi","bool":false},{"option":"Frontalis and mentalis","bool":false},{"option":"Frontalis and orbicularis oculi","bool":false},{"option":"Corrugator supercilii and mentalis","bool":false},{"option":"Frontalis and corrugator supercilii","bool":true}],"id":531},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following contains receptors to detect centrifugal acceleration in order to determine angular acceleration?","answers":[{"option":"Cochlea","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibule","bool":false},{"option":"Saccule","bool":false},{"option":"Utricle","bool":false},{"option":"Semicircular canals","bool":true}],"id":532},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which wall of the middle ear contains an opening for the pharyngotympanic tube?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior wall","bool":false},{"option":"Medial wall","bool":false},{"option":"Roof","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior wall","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral wall","bool":false}],"id":533},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following triangles of neck contains chemoreceptors?","answers":[{"option":"Muscular triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Carotid triangle","bool":true},{"option":"Mental triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Submandibular triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Submental triangle","bool":false}],"id":534},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Third-order neurons of the taste pathway terminate at which of the following areas of the brain?","answers":[{"option":"Broadman's area 6","bool":false},{"option":"Broadman's area 22","bool":false},{"option":"Broca's area","bool":false},{"option":"Opercular insular area","bool":true},{"option":"Broadman's area 17","bool":false}],"id":535},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"A soldier lost his sense of hearing due to exposure to loud sounds. Damage to which of the following organs can result in hearing loss?","answers":[{"option":"Cochlea","bool":false},{"option":"Inner hair cells","bool":true},{"option":"Saccule","bool":false},{"option":"Utricle","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibule","bool":false}],"id":536},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following suprahyoid muscles is supplied by C1 fibers along the hypoglossal nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Stylohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Thyrohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Digastric","bool":false},{"option":"Geniohyoid","bool":true},{"option":"Stylothyroid","bool":false}],"id":537},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following nerves does not pass through the jugular foramen?","answers":[{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal part of accessory nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Nerve to stylopharyngeus","bool":false},{"option":"Cranial part of accessory nerve","bool":false}],"id":538},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is correct about the nerve that is responsible for the physiological peristaltic movements of the gastrointestinal tract?","answers":[{"option":"Originates from pons","bool":false},{"option":"Does not give cardiac branches in the neck","bool":false},{"option":"Exits skull through foramen magnum","bool":false},{"option":"Present outside the carotid sheath","bool":false},{"option":"Joined by cranial part of accessory nerve","bool":true}],"id":539},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following regions has the most abundant distribution of fungiform papillae?","answers":[{"option":"Sides of the tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsum of tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior 2/3rd of a tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Back of the tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Tip of the tongue","bool":true}],"id":540},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following correctly describes the cause of the coloboma?","answers":[{"option":"Abnormal development of optic cup","bool":false},{"option":"Failure of optic cup to close","bool":false},{"option":"Failure of lens vesicle to close","bool":false},{"option":"Failure of choroidal fissure to close","bool":true},{"option":"Failure of separation of eyelids","bool":false}],"id":541},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following correctly describes the function of the myenteric plexus in causing the peristaltic movements of the gut?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibiting circular muscle below the bolus","bool":false},{"option":"Stimulating circular muscles above the bolus","bool":true},{"option":"Inhibiting longitudinal muscles below the bolus","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibiting vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibiting circular muscle above the bolus","bool":false}],"id":542},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following nerves supplies the anterior aspect of the external auditory meatus?","answers":[{"option":"Greater auricular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Auriculotemporal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false}],"id":543},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following structures is damaged if norma lateralis is fractured and cranial nerve VII is affected?","answers":[{"option":"Temporalis","bool":false},{"option":"Stapedius","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral pterygoid","bool":false},{"option":"Masseter","bool":false},{"option":"Tensor tympani","bool":false}],"id":544},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is responsible for the detection of the direction from which the sound is coming?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral geniculate body","bool":false},{"option":"Red nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Medial geniculate body","bool":false},{"option":"Trapezoid body","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral superior olivary nucleus","bool":true}],"id":545},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Parasympathetic fibers arising from which of the following are responsible for the constriction of a pupil and making a lens more convex?","answers":[{"option":"Ciliary ganglion","bool":true},{"option":"Otic ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Submandibular ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Pterygopalatine ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Superior cervical ganglion","bool":false}],"id":546},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Nucleus ambigous does not give fibers to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Nerve to stylopharyngeus","bool":false},{"option":"Constrictor muscles of pharynx","bool":false},{"option":"Superior two-thirds of esophagus","bool":false},{"option":"Tensor veli palatini","bool":true},{"option":"Intrinsic muscles of larynx","bool":false}],"id":547},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"A person comes to the clinic with complaints of drooping of the right upper eyelid and inability to keep his right eye open. Which of the following muscles is most likely involved?","answers":[{"option":"Orbicularis oculi","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior oblique","bool":false},{"option":"Superior rectus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior oblique","bool":false},{"option":"Levator palpebrae superioris","bool":true}],"id":548},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following are found abundantly in the fovea?","answers":[{"option":"Bipolar cells","bool":false},{"option":"Cones","bool":true},{"option":"Rods","bool":false},{"option":"Oxyntic cells","bool":false},{"option":"Endothelial cells","bool":false}],"id":549},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"A few students while conducting research found that some areas of the tongue are stimulated when they get in touch with ionized molecules. Which of the following taste sensations will be produced by these ionized molecules?","answers":[{"option":"Salty and umami","bool":false},{"option":"Salty and sweet","bool":false},{"option":"Bitter and sweet","bool":false},{"option":"Sweet and umami","bool":false},{"option":"Salty and sour","bool":true}],"id":550},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is a voluntary phase of swallowing?","answers":[{"option":"Intestinal phase","bool":false},{"option":"Saliva secretion","bool":false},{"option":"Oral phase","bool":true},{"option":"Pharyngeal phase","bool":false},{"option":"Esophageal phase","bool":false}],"id":551},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is the most important process in swallowing that prevents the entry of food into the larynx?","answers":[{"option":"Upward movement of uvula","bool":false},{"option":"Closure of vocal cords","bool":false},{"option":"Forward movement of larynx","bool":true},{"option":"Upward movement of pharynx","bool":false},{"option":"Opening of epiglottis","bool":false}],"id":552},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following structures is present on the medial wall of the middle ear?","answers":[{"option":"Eustachian tube","bool":false},{"option":"Oval window","bool":true},{"option":"Tympanic membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Epitympanic recess","bool":false},{"option":"Pyramidal process","bool":false}],"id":553},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is not present on the lateral wall of the middle ear?","answers":[{"option":"Round window","bool":true},{"option":"Epitympanic recess","bool":false},{"option":"Handle of malleus","bool":false},{"option":"Chorda tympani","bool":false},{"option":"Attachment of tensor tympani","bool":false}],"id":554},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which muscle is not supplied by the hypoglossal nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Hyoglossus","bool":false},{"option":"Palatoglossus","bool":true},{"option":"Pharyngoglossus","bool":false},{"option":"Styloglossus","bool":false},{"option":"Genioglossus","bool":false}],"id":555},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"The posterior arch of which cervical vertebra has a groove for the vertebral artery?","answers":[{"option":"C4","bool":false},{"option":"C3","bool":false},{"option":"C1","bool":true},{"option":"C2","bool":false},{"option":"C5","bool":false}],"id":556},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following cervical vertebrae is atypical?","answers":[{"option":"C4","bool":false},{"option":"C6","bool":false},{"option":"C5","bool":false},{"option":"C3","bool":false},{"option":"C7","bool":true}],"id":557},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following features is not a characteristic of a typical cervical vertebra?","answers":[{"option":"Triangular vertebral foramen","bool":false},{"option":"Costal facets","bool":true},{"option":"Foramina transversarium","bool":false},{"option":"Bifid spinous process","bool":false},{"option":"Uncinate process on the body","bool":false}],"id":558},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is bound by both the anterior and the posterior belly of the digastric muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Submental triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Muscular triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Carotid triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Submandibular triangle","bool":true},{"option":"Omoclavicular triangle","bool":false}],"id":559},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"The anterior triangle of the neck is bound by which of the following posteriorly?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior border of sternocleidomastoid muscle","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior border of sternocleidomastoid muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Superior belly of omyhyoid muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior belly of digastric muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior belly of digastric muscle","bool":false}],"id":560},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"The two bellies of the digastric muscle have different embryological origins. What is true about the innervation of the muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior belly is innervated by V2","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior belly is innervated by V1","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior belly is innervated by V3","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior belly is innervated by V1","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior belly is innervated by V2","bool":false}],"id":561},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"The pterygopalatine fossa communicates with the orbit through which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Pterygomaxillary fissure","bool":false},{"option":"Pterygoid canal","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior orbital fissure","bool":true},{"option":"Superior orbital fissure","bool":false},{"option":"Optic canal","bool":false}],"id":562},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"The pterygopalatine fossa is bound anteriorly by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Zygomatic process","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenoid","bool":false},{"option":"Maxilla","bool":true},{"option":"Nasal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Hard palate","bool":false}],"id":563},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"At what level is the isthmus of the thyroid gland present?","answers":[{"option":"4th, 5th, and 6th tracheal rings","bool":false},{"option":"3rd, 4th, and 5th tracheal rings","bool":false},{"option":"1st, 2nd, and 3rd tracheal rings","bool":false},{"option":"Oblique line of the thyroid cartilage till the 6th tracheal ring","bool":false},{"option":"2nd, 3rd, and 4th tracheal rings","bool":true}],"id":564},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"The sternocleidomastoid muscle divides the neck into which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Submental and submandibular triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior and posterior triangles","bool":true},{"option":"Carotid and submandibular triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Submental and carotid triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Supraclavicular and suboccipital triangle","bool":false}],"id":565},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"A patient developed winging of the scapula after deep cervical lymph node biopsy. Which nerve is involved?","answers":[{"option":"Accessory spinal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Recurrent laryngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"External laryngeal nerve","bool":false}],"id":566},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"A surgeon noticed bleeding from the pharynx while removing adenoids from a 13-year-old child. Which artery supplies the pharynx?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior alveolar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual artery","bool":false},{"option":"Ascending pharyngeal artery","bool":true},{"option":"Occipital artery","bool":false},{"option":"Facial artery","bool":false}],"id":567},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"The second part of the maxillary artery travels between the heads of which muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Buccinator muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral pterygoid muscle","bool":true},{"option":"Digastric muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Masseter muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Medial pterygoid muscle","bool":false}],"id":568},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which artery's main trunk is divided into mandibular, pterygoid, and pterygopalatine parts?","answers":[{"option":"Superficial temporal artey","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary artery","bool":true},{"option":"Occipital artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior auricular artery","bool":false},{"option":"Facial artery","bool":false}],"id":569},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is not a part of the deep cervical fascia?","answers":[{"option":"Pretracheal fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Prevertebral fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial fascia","bool":true},{"option":"Investing layer","bool":false},{"option":"Carotid sheath","bool":false}],"id":570},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following structures pierces the buccinator muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Facial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Auriculotemporal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Sublingual artery","bool":false},{"option":"Parotid or Stenson's duct","bool":true},{"option":"Deep facial vein","bool":false}],"id":571},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which nerve divides into branches in the parotid gland?","answers":[{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory nerve","bool":false}],"id":572},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"A 25-year-old presented to the emergency with stab wound in the neck at the submandibular triangle and tongue deviation. Which nerve is damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Glossopharyngeal","bool":false},{"option":"Facial","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoglossal","bool":true}],"id":573},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"A surgeon wants to remove a benign swelling from the tip of the nose of a patient under local anesthesia. Which nerve is blocked to anesthise the external nose?","answers":[{"option":"Infraorbital","bool":false},{"option":"Opthalamic","bool":true},{"option":"Maxillary","bool":false},{"option":"Facial","bool":false},{"option":"Mandibular","bool":false}],"id":574},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"A patient came to the otorhinolaryngologist with the complaint of difficulty opening the mouth. Diagnosis of infection of the infratemporal fossa was made. The muscle of mastication occupying most of the upper part of the fossa that helps in opening the mouth was affected. What is the affected muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Buccinator","bool":false},{"option":"Masseter","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral pterygoid","bool":true},{"option":"Medial pterygoid","bool":false},{"option":"Temporalis","bool":false}],"id":575},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"The nerve that supplies the muscles of mastication and is a part of the infratemporal fossa passes through which foramen?","answers":[{"option":"Foramen stylomastoid","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen ovale","bool":true},{"option":"Emissary sphenoid foramen","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen lacerum","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen rotundum","bool":false}],"id":576},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"The upper border of the mandible is thin and is surrounded by two processes; coronoid process anteriorly and condyloid process posteriorly. The two processes are separated by which deep cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Mandibular notch","bool":true},{"option":"Lingula","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar process","bool":false},{"option":"Mental foramen","bool":false},{"option":"Mandibular foramen","bool":false}],"id":577},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"What is the structure present on the anterior surface of the mandible through which inferior alveolar nerve and vessels pass called?","answers":[{"option":"Mandibular foramen","bool":false},{"option":"Mandibular notch","bool":false},{"option":"Mental foramen","bool":true},{"option":"Alveolar process","bool":false},{"option":"Condylar process","bool":false}],"id":578},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"What is the dense fibrous connective tissue joint present between the frontal and the parietal bone called?","answers":[{"option":"Sagittal","bool":false},{"option":"Coronal","bool":true},{"option":"Sphenofrontal","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous","bool":false},{"option":"Lambdoidal","bool":false}],"id":579},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"What is the thinnest part on the lateral wall of the skull where the anteroinferior corner of the parietal bone articulates with the greater wing of the sphenoid bone called?","answers":[{"option":"Pterion","bool":true},{"option":"Asterion","bool":false},{"option":"Nasion","bool":false},{"option":"Supramastoid crest","bool":false},{"option":"Pterygoid humulus","bool":false}],"id":580},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"What foramen is formed by the irregular medial end of the petrous part of the temporal bone, the greater wing of the sphenoid bone, and the basilar part of the occipital bone?","answers":[{"option":"Rotundum","bool":false},{"option":"Lacerum","bool":true},{"option":"Jugular","bool":false},{"option":"Ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Spinosum","bool":false}],"id":581},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which artery supplies the maxillary sinus and the maxillary incisors?","answers":[{"option":"Deep temporal","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior superior alveolar","bool":false},{"option":"Infraorbital","bool":true},{"option":"Pharyngeal","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior alveolar","bool":false}],"id":582},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"A 20-year-old male was brought to the emergency because of a wound on the scalp from a sharp object which was bleeding continuously. Bleeding from the scalp is always profuse due to what reason?","answers":[{"option":"Vessel wall fails to retract","bool":true},{"option":"Wound gape","bool":false},{"option":"Scalp is highly vascular","bool":false},{"option":"Blood vessels lie just beneath the skin","bool":false},{"option":"Large arteries lie in the pericranium","bool":false}],"id":583},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Between which layers does the movement of the scalp take place?","answers":[{"option":"Pericranium and epicranial aponeurosis","bool":false},{"option":"Skin and subcutaneous fat","bool":false},{"option":"Pericranium and loose areolar tissue","bool":true},{"option":"Skin and epicranial aponeurosis","bool":false},{"option":"Pericranium and skull","bool":false}],"id":584},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which artery exits the middle cranial fossa through the optic canal?","answers":[{"option":"Labyrinthine","bool":false},{"option":"Middle meningeal","bool":false},{"option":"Deep temporal","bool":false},{"option":"Opthalamic","bool":true},{"option":"Superficial temporal","bool":false}],"id":585},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following describes the mucosa of the hard palate?","answers":[{"option":"Non-keratinized and has submucosa and minor salivary glands posteromedially","bool":false},{"option":"Keratinized and has submucosa and minor salivary glands anteroinferiorly","bool":false},{"option":"Keratinized and has submucosa and minor salivary glands posterolaterally","bool":false},{"option":"Keratinized and lacks submucosa and minor salivary glands","bool":true},{"option":"Non-keratinized and lacks submucosa and minor salivary glands","bool":false}],"id":586},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is lined by small cuboidal cells in the duct system of the salivary glands?","answers":[{"option":"Intercalated duct","bool":true},{"option":"Interlobular duct","bool":false},{"option":"Intralobular duct","bool":false},{"option":"Striated duct","bool":false},{"option":"Main salivary duct","bool":false}],"id":587},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"What is true regarding the sublingual salivary glands?","answers":[{"option":"Minor gland","bool":false},{"option":"Mucus gland","bool":false},{"option":"Mixed gland","bool":true},{"option":"Serous gland","bool":false},{"option":"Present at the root of the tongue","bool":false}],"id":588},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"The muscle that retracts the temporomandibular joint develops from which structure?","answers":[{"option":"2nd pharyngeal pouch","bool":false},{"option":"2nd pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"3rd pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"1st pharyngeal arch","bool":true},{"option":"1st pharyngeal pouch","bool":false}],"id":589},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"What results from the failure of the fusion of maxillary prominence with the lateral nasal prominence?","answers":[{"option":"Median cleft lip","bool":false},{"option":"Unilateral oblique cleft lip","bool":false},{"option":"Cleft ovula","bool":false},{"option":"Oblique facial cleft","bool":true},{"option":"Cleft palate","bool":false}],"id":590},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"The posterior one-third of the tongue develops from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Hypopharyngeal eminence","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral lingual swelling","bool":false},{"option":"Epiglottal swelling","bool":false},{"option":"Copula","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculum impar","bool":false}],"id":591},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"A patient visited an eye outpatient department with the complaint of loss of right field of vision in both eyes. Which of the following is damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Right optic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Left optic tract","bool":true},{"option":"Left optic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Optic chiasma","bool":false},{"option":"Right optic nerve","bool":false}],"id":592},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"The magnocellular layer of the lateral geniculate body is concerned with which visual information?","answers":[{"option":"Greater spacial resolution","bool":false},{"option":"Lower temporal resolution","bool":false},{"option":"Color vision","bool":false},{"option":"Black-and-white vision","bool":true},{"option":"Discriminating fine details","bool":false}],"id":593},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"A group of researchers wanted to identify substances which require charged ions for taste receptor stimulation. The charged ions can be a combination of which tastes?","answers":[{"option":"Bitter and sour","bool":false},{"option":"Salty and umami","bool":false},{"option":"Salty and sour","bool":true},{"option":"Sweet and sour","bool":false},{"option":"Sweet and umami","bool":false}],"id":594},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"A high taste threshold in smokers is due to damage to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Taste center in cerebral cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Nerve fibers carrying taste sensation","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus of tractus solitarius","bool":false},{"option":"Internal damage to papilla","bool":true},{"option":"External damage to taste buds","bool":false}],"id":595},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which area of the cerebral cortex is responsible for the conscious perception, discrimination and analysis of odor?","answers":[{"option":"Amygdala","bool":false},{"option":"Hippocampus","bool":false},{"option":"Prepyriform cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Orbitofrontal cortex","bool":true}],"id":596},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"A patient lost his ability to smell. Which cells in his nasal mucosa were most likely damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Epithelial","bool":false},{"option":"Multipolar","bool":false},{"option":"Bipolar","bool":true},{"option":"Unipolar","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudo unipolar","bool":false}],"id":597},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which center of the brain controls the rapid directional movement of the eyes?","answers":[{"option":"Superior colliculus","bool":true},{"option":"Suprachiasmatic nucleus of the hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Paraventricular nucleus of the hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Pretectal nuclei in the midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Ventral lateral geniculate nucleus of the thalamus","bool":false}],"id":598},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"A 35-year-old male presents to the clinic with a decrease in near vision while distant vision is normal. Retinoscopy at 1-meter shows that he requires spherical lens for the correction of vision. Which error of refraction is present in the patient?","answers":[{"option":"Hypermetropia","bool":true},{"option":"Presbyopia","bool":false},{"option":"Myopia","bool":false},{"option":"Accommodation paralysis","bool":false},{"option":"Astigmatism","bool":false}],"id":599},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"A child presents with difficulty in seeing the blackboard while sitting at the benches at the back in school. What is the most likely cause of his condition?","answers":[{"option":"Presbyopia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypermetropia","bool":false},{"option":"Astigmatism","bool":false},{"option":"Accommodation paralysis","bool":false},{"option":"Myopia","bool":true}],"id":600},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Myopia is most commonly caused by an increase in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Thickness of the lens","bool":false},{"option":"Anteroposterior diameter of the eyeball","bool":true},{"option":"Viscosity of vitreous humor","bool":false},{"option":"Thickness of the cornea","bool":false},{"option":"Viscosity of aqueous humor","bool":false}],"id":601},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"A 44-year-old man visits his ophthalmologist with the complaint of increasing difficulty in reading the newspaper. His vision problem is due the inability to contract which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Extraocular muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Suspensory ligaments","bool":false},{"option":"Radial muscles of the iris","bool":false},{"option":"Pupil","bool":false},{"option":"Ciliary body","bool":true}],"id":602},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Light energy activates rhodopsin which is a key process in phototransduction. What is the activated form of rhodopsin that excites electrical changes in the rods?","answers":[{"option":"Metarhodopsin-II","bool":true},{"option":"11-trans retinal","bool":false},{"option":"Bathorhodopsin","bool":false},{"option":"Metarhodopsin-I","bool":false},{"option":"Lumirhodopsin","bool":false}],"id":603},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"A 54-year-old man was operated for neuronal tumor at the base of the brain. He complained of visual field defect postoperatively. Brain MRI showed lesion in the right optic tract. Which visual field defect is present in the patient?","answers":[{"option":"Binasal hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Right homonymous hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Left homonymous hemianopia","bool":true},{"option":"Bitemporal hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Left sided anopia","bool":false}],"id":604},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Rhodopsin is a conjugated protein present in the rods of the retina. What is its composition?","answers":[{"option":"Opsin and retinoic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Keratin and 11-cis-retinal","bool":false},{"option":"Crystalline and retinoic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Crystalline and 11-cis-retinal","bool":false},{"option":"Opsin and 11-cis-retinal","bool":true}],"id":605},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Most infants are born with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Emmetropia","bool":false},{"option":"Myopia","bool":false},{"option":"Amblyopia","bool":false},{"option":"Astigmatism","bool":false},{"option":"Hypermetropia","bool":true}],"id":606},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"The five broad personality traits described by theory are extraversion, agreeableness, openness, conscientiousness, and neuroticism. Personality evaluation of Ali indicates that he has the tendency to be responsible, hard-working, goal-directed, organized and to adhere to norms and rules. Based on the findings, Ali must have scored high on which scale of big five personality test?","answers":[{"option":"Agreeableness","bool":false},{"option":"Extraversion","bool":false},{"option":"Openness","bool":false},{"option":"Neuroticism","bool":false},{"option":"Conscientiousness","bool":true}],"id":607},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following muscles forms the roof of the suboccipital triangle of the neck?","answers":[{"option":"Rectus capitis posterior minor","bool":false},{"option":"Semispinalis capitis","bool":true},{"option":"Obliquus capitis inferior","bool":false},{"option":"Rectus capitis posterior major","bool":false},{"option":"Obliquus capitis superior","bool":false}],"id":608},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"The duct of the largest salivary gland, which forms a major part of salivary secretions, opens into which of the following regions of the oral cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Caruncula","bool":false},{"option":"Side of the lingual frenulum","bool":false},{"option":"Floor of the mouth","bool":false},{"option":"Opposite to second maxillary molar tooth","bool":true},{"option":"Sublingual fossa","bool":false}],"id":609},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"The pharyngeal plexus lies on which of the following muscles of the pharynx?","answers":[{"option":"Superior pharyngeal constrictor","bool":false},{"option":"Salpingopharyngeus","bool":false},{"option":"Stylopharyngeus","bool":false},{"option":"Middle pharyngeal constrictor","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior pharyngeal constrictor","bool":false}],"id":610},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following cervical vertebrae has an odontoid process?","answers":[{"option":"C2","bool":true},{"option":"C3","bool":false},{"option":"C7","bool":false},{"option":"C4","bool":false},{"option":"C1","bool":false}],"id":611},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"A 44-year-old male patient presents to the outpatient clinic with a progressive loss of temporal field of vision. Visual field testing confirms bitemporal hemianopia. When compressed, which of the following structures is most likely to result in this defect?","answers":[{"option":"Visual cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Optic chiasma","bool":true},{"option":"Optic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Optic radiations","bool":false},{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":false}],"id":612},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following types of receptors is the taste receptor characterized as?","answers":[{"option":"Osmoreceptors","bool":false},{"option":"Mechanoreceptor","bool":false},{"option":"Baroreceptors","bool":false},{"option":"Pacinian corpuscles","bool":false},{"option":"Chemoreceptor","bool":true}],"id":613},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"A 32-year-old male patient presents to the outpatient clinic with the complaint of excessive droopiness of the left eyelid (ptosis). Loss of function of which of the following muscles can result in this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Orbicularis oculi","bool":false},{"option":"Levator palpebrae superioris","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior oblique","bool":false},{"option":"Superior oblique","bool":false},{"option":"Superior rectus","bool":false}],"id":614},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"A soldier hears the sound of gunshots and follows in the direction of the sound. Which of the following structures is responsible for the detection of the direction from which the sound is coming?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral superior olivary nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Cochlear nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior colliculus","bool":false},{"option":"Medial superior olivary nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral geniculate body","bool":false}],"id":615},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following arteries is located in the suboccipital triangle?","answers":[{"option":"Third part of vertebral artery","bool":true},{"option":"Suboccipital artery","bool":false},{"option":"Occipital artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior auricular artery","bool":false},{"option":"Third part of basilar artery","bool":false}],"id":616},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"A 59-year-old male patient presents to the ophthalmology clinic with a complaint of double vision. On evaluation, it is found that the muscle responsible for lateral rotation of the eye is paralyzed. Which of the following nerves innervates this muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Oculomotor nerve","bool":false}],"id":617},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"A school counselor observes a student who works really hard and is highly ambitious toward his goal, but he can be very competitive and self-critical. In certain situations, he also tends to be impatient and shows anger management issues. Which of the following personality types is this student most likely to have?","answers":[{"option":"Type B","bool":false},{"option":"Type D","bool":false},{"option":"Type A","bool":true},{"option":"Type C","bool":false},{"option":"Type E","bool":false}],"id":618},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following landmarks in the skull of an adult marks the location of the posterior fontanelle in neonates?","answers":[{"option":"Asterion","bool":false},{"option":"Lambda","bool":true},{"option":"Bregma","bool":false},{"option":"Pterion","bool":false},{"option":"Nasion","bool":false}],"id":619},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following types of glands are the major salivary glands categorized under?","answers":[{"option":"Simple tubuloacinar glands","bool":false},{"option":"Compound acinar gland","bool":false},{"option":"Compound tubular glands","bool":false},{"option":"Simple acinar glands","bool":false},{"option":"Compound tubuloacinar glands","bool":true}],"id":620},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"The maxillary artery which is embedded in the parotid gland supplies the deep tissue of the face. It is a terminal branch of which of the following arteries?","answers":[{"option":"Facial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Vertebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"External carotid artery","bool":true},{"option":"Internal carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Subclavian artery","bool":false}],"id":621},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Pituitary adenomas can result in compression of the pituitary stalk. Which of the following is the most likely indication of compression of the pituitary stalk?","answers":[{"option":"Headache","bool":false},{"option":"Increased serum ADH","bool":false},{"option":"Vomiting","bool":false},{"option":"Memory loss","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperprolactinemia","bool":true}],"id":622},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"The superior oblique muscle is supplied by which of the following cranial nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Superior branch of oculomotor nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior branch of oculomotor nerve","bool":false}],"id":623},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following nerves supplies the anterior wall of the external acoustic meatus?","answers":[{"option":"Greater auricular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Lesser occipital nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Auriculotemporal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Auricular branch of vagus nerve","bool":false}],"id":624},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following muscles of facial expression is involved in smiling?","answers":[{"option":"Levator labi superioris","bool":false},{"option":"Risorius","bool":false},{"option":"Zygomaticus major","bool":true},{"option":"Levator anguli oris","bool":false},{"option":"Corrugator supercilii","bool":false}],"id":625},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"The philtrum of the upper lip is derived from which of the following embryological structures?","answers":[{"option":"Frontonasal prominence and maxillary prominence","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary prominence and lateral nasal prominence","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral nasal prominence and medial nasal prominence","bool":false},{"option":"Medial nasal prominence and maxillary prominence","bool":true},{"option":"Maxillary prominence only","bool":false}],"id":626},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"A 36-year-old male patient presents to the outpatient clinic with an infection of the nasal and paranasal sinuses. He complains of a headache and vision problems. A CT scan reveals cavernous sinus thrombosis. Which of the following veins is the most likely route of spread of infection from the area around the nose and upper lips to the cavernous sinus?","answers":[{"option":"Supraorbital vein","bool":false},{"option":"Superior ophthalmic vein","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior ophthalmic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Infraorbital vein","bool":false},{"option":"Supratrochlear vein","bool":false}],"id":627},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"A greater palatine nerve block will anesthetize which of the following areas of the oral cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Buccal gingivae of molars","bool":false},{"option":"Palatal mucosa and lingual gingivae anterior to maxillary canine teeth","bool":false},{"option":"Palatal mucosa and lingual gingivae posterior to maxillary canine teeth","bool":true},{"option":"Palatine mucosa only","bool":false},{"option":"Buccal gingivae of premolars","bool":false}],"id":628},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following layers of the scalps contains the blood vessels supplying the scalp?","answers":[{"option":"Pericranium","bool":false},{"option":"Epicranial aponeurosis","bool":false},{"option":"Skin","bool":false},{"option":"Loose areolar connective tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Connective tissue","bool":true}],"id":629},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Congenital aphakia results when an important structure of the eye fails to develop. Which of the following embryonic layers does this structure originate from?","answers":[{"option":"Endoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Neuroectoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Surface ectoderm","bool":true},{"option":"Paraxial mesoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Mesoderm","bool":false}],"id":630},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following layers of the cornea does not have the ability to regenerate once damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Descemet's membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Corneal stroma","bool":false},{"option":"Bowman's membrane","bool":true},{"option":"Corneal endothelium","bool":false},{"option":"Corneal epithelium","bool":false}],"id":631},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is the primary function of the superior oblique?","answers":[{"option":"Depression","bool":false},{"option":"Abduction","bool":false},{"option":"Extorsion","bool":false},{"option":"Adduction","bool":false},{"option":"Intorsion","bool":true}],"id":632},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"The cells of the thyroid gland, which secrete calcitonin, are derived from which of the following embryological structures?","answers":[{"option":"Second pharyngeal pouch","bool":false},{"option":"Ultimobranchial body","bool":true},{"option":"Second pharyngeal cleft","bool":false},{"option":"Fourth pharyngeal cleft","bool":false},{"option":"First pharyngeal pouch","bool":false}],"id":633},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"A child is brought to the emergency room with an injury to the nasal septum. Which of the following bones are most likely to be affected?","answers":[{"option":"Nasal bones only","bool":false},{"option":"Cribriform plate of ethmoid and vomer","bool":false},{"option":"Perpendicular plate of ethmoid and vomer","bool":true},{"option":"Maxillary and nasal bones","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal and frontal bones","bool":false}],"id":634},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is the correct term for age-related hearing loss?","answers":[{"option":"Hypoacusis","bool":false},{"option":"Otosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Presbyopia","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperacusis","bool":false},{"option":"Presbycusis","bool":true}],"id":635},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"A child suffers from a lesion of the nasociliary ganglion. Which of the following nerves supplies the preganglionic parasympathetic fibers to this ganglion?","answers":[{"option":"Nerve to inferior oblique","bool":false},{"option":"Short ciliary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Nasociliary nerve","bool":false}],"id":636},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following arteries is a terminal branch of the right common carotid artery?","answers":[{"option":"Ascending pharyngeal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Superior thyroid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary artery","bool":false},{"option":"Facial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Internal carotid artery","bool":true}],"id":637},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following muscles of the larynx is involved in the abduction of the vocal cords?","answers":[{"option":"Cricothyroid","bool":false},{"option":"Vocalis","bool":false},{"option":"Transverse arytenoid","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior cricoarytenoid","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral cricoarytenoid","bool":false}],"id":638},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following nerves supplies preganglionic parasympathetic nerve fibers to the otic ganglion?","answers":[{"option":"Nasociliary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Short ciliary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Chorda tympani","bool":false},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Auricutemporal nerve","bool":false}],"id":639},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following disorders requires surgical removal?","answers":[{"option":"Acoustic neuroma","bool":true},{"option":"Hyperacusis","bool":false},{"option":"Otitis media","bool":false},{"option":"Presbycusis","bool":false},{"option":"Meningitis","bool":false}],"id":640},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"The pulse of the facial artery can be palpated over the anteroinferior angle of which of the following muscles?","answers":[{"option":"Masseter","bool":true},{"option":"Buccinator","bool":false},{"option":"Temporalis","bool":false},{"option":"Orbicularis oris","bool":false},{"option":"Zygomaticus major","bool":false}],"id":641},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following vessels is most commonly involved in the setting of an epidural hematoma?","answers":[{"option":"Emissary veins","bool":false},{"option":"Middle meningeal artery","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior meningeal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Dural venous sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior meningeal artery","bool":false}],"id":642},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following arteries is most likely to be damaged in an injury to the subclavian triangle of the neck?","answers":[{"option":"External carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Ascending pharyngeal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Third part of subclavian artery","bool":true},{"option":"Third part of vertebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Facial artery","bool":false}],"id":643},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"The hyoid bone develops from which of the following embryological structures?","answers":[{"option":"First and second pharyngeal arches","bool":false},{"option":"First and second pharyngeal pouches","bool":false},{"option":"Fourth and sixth pharyngeal arches","bool":false},{"option":"Second and third pharyngeal arches","bool":true},{"option":"Second and third pharyngeal pouches","bool":false}],"id":644},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022"],"question":"Which of the following correctly describes the sensory innervation of the superior laryngeal nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Larynx below the vocal cords","bool":false},{"option":"Vocal cords only","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior wall of larynx","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior wall of larynx","bool":false},{"option":"Larynx above the vocal cords","bool":true}],"id":645},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"Which muscle is pierced by the parotid duct?","answers":[{"option":"Buccinator","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral pterygoid","bool":false},{"option":"Zygomaticus major","bool":false},{"option":"Medial pterygoid","bool":false},{"option":"Masseter","bool":false}],"id":646},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"What is the refractive index of the lens?","answers":[{"option":"1.00","bool":false},{"option":"1.40","bool":true},{"option":"1.38","bool":false},{"option":"1.34","bool":false},{"option":"1.33","bool":false}],"id":647},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"An 18-year-old man comes to the emergency department with the complaint of inability to completely open his mouth and numbness on his chin and gingiva on his lower jaw after a motorbike accident. On x-ray, diagnosis of fracture of symphysis menti is made. Which nerve is responsible for the numbness?","answers":[{"option":"Auricotemporal","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual","bool":false},{"option":"Superior alveolar","bool":false},{"option":"Buccal","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior alveolar","bool":true}],"id":648},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"A patient is brought into the emergency department after sustaining a gunshot wound in the temporal fossa. On examination, there is bleeding from the ear. CT scan reveals a fracture of the bony floor of the temporal fossa. Which clinically important structure lies in the floor of the temporal fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Asterion","bool":false},{"option":"Inion","bool":false},{"option":"Nasion","bool":false},{"option":"Pterion","bool":true},{"option":"Obelion","bool":false}],"id":649},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"A boy complains of loss of sensation from the anterior aspect of the tongue. In which nuclei of the brainstem does the nerve carrying the concerned sensation end?","answers":[{"option":"Nucleus of tractus solitaries","bool":true},{"option":"Superior salivatory nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus ambiguous","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal nucleus of trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Motor nucleus of facial","bool":false}],"id":650},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"An athlete arrives at the emergency department with a dislocated jaw due to a fall injury while running. He complains of difficulty in swallowing and speaking. Reduction of the mandible is prescribed as a treatment plan. Which muscle initiates the depression of the dislocated bone?","answers":[{"option":"Temporalis","bool":false},{"option":"Medial pterygoid","bool":false},{"option":"Masseter","bool":false},{"option":"Buccinator","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral pterygoid","bool":true}],"id":651},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"A boxer comes to the emergency department due to a blowout fracture caused by a direct hard blow to his face by his opponent. The x-ray confirms a fracture of the orbital floor. Which nerve is most likely to be damaged due to the blowout?","answers":[{"option":"Supraorbital","bool":false},{"option":"Supratrochlear","bool":false},{"option":"Optic","bool":false},{"option":"Short ciliary","bool":false},{"option":"Infraorbital","bool":true}],"id":652},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"The infraorbital fissure is posteriorly between the maxilla and the greater wing of the sphenoid bone. Which fossa communicates with this fissure?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior cranial","bool":false},{"option":"Infratemporal","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior cranial","bool":false},{"option":"Supratemporal","bool":false},{"option":"Pterygopalatine","bool":true}],"id":653},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"Second-year medical students were asked to expose the muscles of sub-occipital triangle on a cadaver. Which of the following muscles is likely to be found?","answers":[{"option":"Longus capitis","bool":false},{"option":"Rectus capitis posterior","bool":true},{"option":"Scalene medius","bool":false},{"option":"Levator scapulae","bool":false},{"option":"Splenius capitis","bool":false}],"id":654},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"During rhinoplasty, an ENT surgeon needs to give an incision to the five layers of the external nose. In which of the following layers lie the muscles?","answers":[{"option":"Third","bool":true},{"option":"Forth","bool":false},{"option":"First","bool":false},{"option":"Second","bool":false},{"option":"Fifth","bool":false}],"id":655},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"A 25-year-old male presents to the emergency department with a stab wound in the neck region directed into the submandibular triangle with tongue deviation. Which of the following nerves was damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Glossopharyngeal","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal","bool":false},{"option":"Facial","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoglossal","bool":true}],"id":656},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"What is the action of the superior oblique muscle on the eyeball?","answers":[{"option":"Adduction, intorsion, and depression","bool":false},{"option":"Adduction, extorsion, and depression","bool":false},{"option":"Abduction, intorsion, and depression","bool":true},{"option":"Abduction, extorsion, and elevation","bool":false},{"option":"Adduction, intorsion, and elevation","bool":false}],"id":657},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"Which movement of the eyeball will occur when the superior rectus and inferior oblique contract together?","answers":[{"option":"Elevation","bool":true},{"option":"Abduction","bool":false},{"option":"Adduction","bool":false},{"option":"Intorsion","bool":false},{"option":"Depression","bool":false}],"id":658},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"Which movement of the eyeball will occur when the inferior rectus and superior oblique contract together?","answers":[{"option":"Depression","bool":true},{"option":"Adduction","bool":false},{"option":"Elevation","bool":false},{"option":"Abduction","bool":false},{"option":"Intorsion","bool":false}],"id":659},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"The pterygopalatine fossa communicates with the middle cranial fossa through which of the following passages?","answers":[{"option":"Pterygomaxillary fissure","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenopalatine foramen","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior orbital fissure","bool":false},{"option":"Palatovaginal canal","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen rotundum","bool":true}],"id":660},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"Olfactory epithelium can get damaged by inhalation of toxic fumes and causes physical injury to the nose by the use of nasal spray. What can this lead to?","answers":[{"option":"Insomnia","bool":false},{"option":"Anosmia","bool":true},{"option":"Diplopia","bool":false},{"option":"Anorexia","bool":false},{"option":"Hemianopia","bool":false}],"id":661},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"Which nerve supplies the platysma muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Mandibular branch of trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Branch of glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Branch of accessory spinal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Cervical branch of facial nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Branch of vagus nerve","bool":false}],"id":662},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"Which nerve lesion results in contralateral motor loss of the inferior half of the face?","answers":[{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Corticonuclear","bool":true},{"option":"Hypoglossal","bool":false},{"option":"Corticospinal","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory","bool":false}],"id":663},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"A newborn may present with caput succedaneum, leading to prolonged labor. The swelling is present in which layer of the scalp?","answers":[{"option":"Scalp and periosteum","bool":false},{"option":"Aponeurosis and areolar tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Connective tissue and aponeurosis","bool":true},{"option":"Loose areolar tissue and pericranium","bool":false},{"option":"Skin and connective tissue","bool":false}],"id":664},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"Which type of salivary gland secretes thin, watery, and rich in enzyme fluid only?","answers":[{"option":"Von Ebners","bool":false},{"option":"Sublingual","bool":false},{"option":"Glands of palate","bool":false},{"option":"Parotid","bool":true},{"option":"Submandibular","bool":false}],"id":665},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"Which nerve passes through the root of the neck?","answers":[{"option":"Accessory cranial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoglossal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Vestibulocochlear nerve","bool":false}],"id":666},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"Which of the following structures is a prominent feature of the lateral wall of the middle ear cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Canal for the tensor tympani muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Aditus to mastoid antrum","bool":false},{"option":"Pyramidal process","bool":false},{"option":"Epitympanic recess","bool":true},{"option":"Facial canal","bool":false}],"id":667},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"The medial wall of the pterygopalatine fossa has which of the following opening?","answers":[{"option":"Foramen rotundum","bool":false},{"option":"Pterygomaxillary fissure","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenopalatine foramen","bool":true},{"option":"Pterygoid canal","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior orbital fissure","bool":false}],"id":668},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"Histological features of an organ demonstrated mucosa lined by stratified squamous nonkeratinized epithelium with papillae. The core of the organ is of skeletal muscles. Which of the following organ matches this description?","answers":[{"option":"Pharynx","bool":false},{"option":"Hard palate","bool":false},{"option":"Soft palate","bool":false},{"option":"Palatine tonsils","bool":false},{"option":"Tongue","bool":true}],"id":669},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"In a histology practical, some students were asked a question regarding a major salivary gland of pure serous nature. Trauma to that salivary gland causes damage to the nerve resulting in the loss of a section of the muscle of facial expression. Which nerve is involved?","answers":[{"option":"Glossopharyngeal","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus","bool":false},{"option":"Occulomotor","bool":false},{"option":"Facial","bool":true},{"option":"Trochlear","bool":false}],"id":670},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"A histopathologist was observing a slide of a gland under the microscope. It had darkly stained acini with the apical portion of cells filled with secretory granules with striated ducts. Which gland was being observed by the histopathologist?","answers":[{"option":"Sublingual","bool":false},{"option":"Thyroid","bool":false},{"option":"Parotid","bool":true},{"option":"Parathyroid","bool":false},{"option":"Submandibular","bool":false}],"id":671},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"While observing the microscopic features of the tongue, which of the following papillae is thread-like, deficient in taste buds, and present on the superior surface of the tongue?","answers":[{"option":"Vallate","bool":false},{"option":"Fungiform","bool":false},{"option":"Circumvallate","bool":false},{"option":"Filiform","bool":true},{"option":"Foliate","bool":false}],"id":672},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"Meibomian glands are modified sebaceous glands present on which layer of the eyelid?","answers":[{"option":"Epidermis of skin","bool":false},{"option":"Dermis of skin","bool":false},{"option":"Tarsal plate","bool":true},{"option":"Mucous layer","bool":false},{"option":"Muscular layer","bool":false}],"id":673},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"The cancer of the submandibular gland has involved a duct lined by low columnar secretory cells having multiple mitochondria at the base. Also, the duct involved is intralobular. Which of the following ducts is involved?","answers":[{"option":"Intercalated duct","bool":false},{"option":"Terminal duct","bool":false},{"option":"Excretory duct","bool":false},{"option":"Interlobular duct","bool":false},{"option":"Striated ducts","bool":true}],"id":674},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"Which of the following layers of the cornea cannot regenerate, leading to corneal scarring?","answers":[{"option":"Endothelium","bool":false},{"option":"Descemets membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Stroma","bool":false},{"option":"Epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Bowman's membrane","bool":true}],"id":675},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"A patient is seen in the neurosurgery clinic with an MRI confirmed pituitary adenoma. Surgical resection of the adenoma is planned. When considering the surgical approach, which paranasal sinus provides access to the pituitary gland?","answers":[{"option":"Frontal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior ethmoidal air cells","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Middle ethmoidal air cells","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenoid sinus","bool":true}],"id":676},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"A patient complains of frontal sinus pressure. You determine that it is an infection and administer mucosal shrinking medication. The mucous will then drain into the nasal cavity through which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Nasolacrimal duct","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior nasal meatus","bool":false},{"option":"Spheno-ethmoidal recess","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenopalatine canal","bool":false},{"option":"Semilunar hiatus","bool":true}],"id":677},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"Which of the following veins is not a tributary of the pterygoid venous plexus?","answers":[{"option":"Infraorbital vein","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenopalatine vein","bool":false},{"option":"Greater palatine vein","bool":false},{"option":"Pharyngeal vein","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary vein","bool":true}],"id":678},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"Which pharyngeal arches are the middle ear ossicles derived from?","answers":[{"option":"4th and 6th","bool":false},{"option":"3rd and 6th","bool":false},{"option":"3rd and 4th","bool":false},{"option":"2nd and 3rd","bool":false},{"option":"1st and 2nd","bool":true}],"id":679},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"Failure of fusion of which of the following causes unilateral oblique cleft lip?","answers":[{"option":"Frontonasal prominence with maxillary prominence","bool":false},{"option":"Two medial nasal prominence","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary prominence with lateral nasal prominence","bool":false},{"option":"Two mandibular prominence","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary prominence with medial nasal prominence","bool":true}],"id":680},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"Which part does the sensory retina develop from?","answers":[{"option":"Pars ciliaris retinae","bool":false},{"option":"Pars optica retinae","bool":true},{"option":"Outer layer of optic cup","bool":false},{"option":"Pars ividica retinae","bool":false},{"option":"Pars ceca retinae","bool":false}],"id":681},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"What is the visual faculty that allows us to take in information about space in three dimensions (3D)?","answers":[{"option":"Binocular vision","bool":false},{"option":"Stereopsis","bool":true},{"option":"Visual acuity","bool":false},{"option":"Stereognosis","bool":false},{"option":"Field of vision","bool":false}],"id":682},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"A man in his fifties presents with throbbing eye discomfort, a red eye, headache, and blurred vision. The intraocular pressure was at 60 mmHg, and the opthalmologist suspected glaucoma. What level of intraocular pressure would protect the optic nerve and halt eyesight loss?","answers":[{"option":"30 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"15 mmHg","bool":true},{"option":"10 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"25 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"5 mmHg","bool":false}],"id":683},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"A fourth grader complained that he could not see the board from the back of the classroom. His eyes were checked by an opthalmologist after his mother took him to have any refractive issues corrected. What was the ultimate diagnosis, and which lens was given for correction?","answers":[{"option":"Near sightedness and gave spherical lenses for correction","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperopia and gave concave lenses for correction","bool":false},{"option":"Myopia and gave spherical lenses for correction","bool":false},{"option":"Far sightedness and gave spherical lenses for correction","bool":false},{"option":"Near sightedness and gave concave lenses for correction","bool":true}],"id":684},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"A patient visits the outpatient department due to ongoing headache symptoms. He claims to be experiencing visual issues, including an inability to see what is coming from the side. This resulted in the suspension of his driving privileges. Based on the information provided, his condition is described as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Homonymous hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Bitemporal hemianopia","bool":true},{"option":"Binasal hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Raised intraocular pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Bilateral lesion of optic tract","bool":false}],"id":685},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"In a fraction of a second, after rhodopsin has absorbed light energy, it begins to degrade. Which of these is the immediate product?","answers":[{"option":"Metarhodopsin-I","bool":false},{"option":"Bathorhodopsin","bool":true},{"option":"Lumirhodopsin","bool":false},{"option":"Scotopsin","bool":false},{"option":"Metarhodopsin-II","bool":false}],"id":686},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"Which of the following cells sends inhibitory signals backward to regulate the lateral spread of visual signals to neighboring cells to help control the degree of contrast in the visual image?","answers":[{"option":"Ganglion cell","bool":false},{"option":"Bipolar cell","bool":false},{"option":"Amacrine cell","bool":false},{"option":"Horizontal cell","bool":false},{"option":"Interplexiform cell","bool":true}],"id":687},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"Which neurotransmitter is released by rods and cones at their synapses with bipolar cells?","answers":[{"option":"GABA","bool":false},{"option":"Glycine","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamate","bool":true},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false}],"id":688},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"Once presbyopia has set in, each eye maintains a fixed focus at a nearly constant distance which is unique to the individual's eye anatomy. Which of the following lenses would be the best for a person of advanced age to use to ensure clear vision at all distances?","answers":[{"option":"Cylindrical lens","bool":false},{"option":"Bifocal lens","bool":true},{"option":"Spherical lens","bool":false},{"option":"Biconvex lens","bool":false},{"option":"Biconcave lens","bool":false}],"id":689},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"Which of the following sensory modalities is conveyed by free nerve endings?","answers":[{"option":"Smell","bool":false},{"option":"Taste","bool":false},{"option":"Temperature","bool":true},{"option":"Vision","bool":false},{"option":"Sound","bool":false}],"id":690},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"Which of the following factors is accountable for the emotions and memories linked to the sense of smell?","answers":[{"option":"Frontal cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Postcentral gyrus","bool":false},{"option":"Olfactory cortex","bool":true},{"option":"Limbus system","bool":false},{"option":"Temporal lobe","bool":false}],"id":691},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"In which of the following situations does one get the greatest depth of focus?","answers":[{"option":"Extremely small size of pupil","bool":true},{"option":"Contraction of ciliary muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Large pupil","bool":false},{"option":"Relaxation of ciliary muscle","bool":false},{"option":"In dark environment","bool":false}],"id":692},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"Which protein is responsible for absorbing light in the retina and for vision?","answers":[{"option":"Fibrin","bool":false},{"option":"Keratin","bool":false},{"option":"Collagen","bool":false},{"option":"Melanin","bool":false},{"option":"Rhodopsin","bool":true}],"id":693},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"Which biochemical form of vitamin A is found in the visual cycle?","answers":[{"option":"Retinone","bool":false},{"option":"Retinyl ester","bool":false},{"option":"Retinaldehyde","bool":true},{"option":"Retinoic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Retinol","bool":false}],"id":694},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"What disease is caused by the deficiency of vitamin A?","answers":[{"option":"Strabismus","bool":false},{"option":"Amblyopia","bool":false},{"option":"Xeropthalmia","bool":true},{"option":"Pernicious anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Glaucoma","bool":false}],"id":695},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"A team of doctors needs to know the exact source of intestinal bleeding in a patient. They radiolabeled (and radioactive atoms) a sample of red blood cells taken from a patient. They then reinject the blood to follow the path of blood in the patient. Which of the following technique is used?","answers":[{"option":"X ray","bool":false},{"option":"CT scan","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound scan","bool":false},{"option":"SPECT scan","bool":true},{"option":"MRI scan","bool":false}],"id":696},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"A professor was comparing nuclear medicine with conventional radiology. Among the following, which is a characteristic feature of nuclear medicine procedure?","answers":[{"option":"Cannot elaborate upon body functions","bool":false},{"option":"Shows structure only","bool":false},{"option":"Beams of radiation pass through the body","bool":false},{"option":"Radioactive material is injected, ingested, or inhaled","bool":true},{"option":"Mainly used in diagnosis","bool":false}],"id":697},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"A patient intends to seek advice for his forthcoming travel tour to Kenya. He visits the clinic for advice on vaccination, precautions, and chemoprophylaxis. Among the following, which branch of medicine deals specifically with the patient's queries?","answers":[{"option":"Geriatrics","bool":false},{"option":"Emporiatrics","bool":true},{"option":"Infectious diseases","bool":false},{"option":"Epidemiology","bool":false},{"option":"Geriatric medicine","bool":false}],"id":698},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"A 50-year-old man comes to the outpatient department with the feeling as if he was floating or if the world was spinning. The affected nerve responsible for this condition receives motor sensation from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Cochlea","bool":false},{"option":"Saccule","bool":false},{"option":"Semicircular canal","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibule","bool":true},{"option":"Utricle","bool":false}],"id":699},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"A patient comes to the family physician with a complaint of pain in the temporomandibular joint that gets worse during the opening of the mouth. After examination and investigation, diagnosis of forward dislocation of mandible is made. Which factor does not normally oppose the forward movement of this bone?","answers":[{"option":"Masseter","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral pterygoid","bool":true},{"option":"Medial pterygoid","bool":false},{"option":"Temporalis (posterior fibres)","bool":false},{"option":"Articular eminence","bool":false}],"id":700},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"The presynaptic parasympathetic fibers to the otic ganglion in the infratemporal fossa are carried by which of the following nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Carotid sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Deep petrosal","bool":false},{"option":"Lesser petrosal","bool":true},{"option":"Auriculotemporal","bool":false},{"option":"Greater petrosal","bool":false}],"id":701},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"Involuntary fixation is the ability to keep a selected object in your visual field once it has been found via a combination of drifting and flickering movements. Which of the following is most responsible for the loss of this ability?","answers":[{"option":"Superior colliculus","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior colliculus","bool":false},{"option":"Medial longitudinal fasciculus","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear nerve nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior colliculus muscle","bool":false}],"id":702},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"Which of the following pupillary responses is seen in the Argyll Robertson pupil?","answers":[{"option":"Failure to respond to accommodation but responds to light","bool":false},{"option":"Normal response to light and accommodation","bool":false},{"option":"Failure to respond to accommodation only","bool":false},{"option":"Failure to respond to both accommodation and light","bool":false},{"option":"Failure to respond to light but responds to accommodation","bool":true}],"id":703},{"info":["2nd-year/head-and-neck/compiled","2nd-year/head-and-neck/2023"],"question":"How many times as much force is applied to the cochlear fluid as applied to the tympanic membrane by sound waves?","answers":[{"option":"17 folds","bool":false},{"option":"30 folds","bool":false},{"option":"1.3 folds","bool":false},{"option":"22 folds","bool":true},{"option":"55 folds","bool":false}],"id":704}]
export default arr